In the last course section
we learned how proper naming can help us
with the code readability
and therefore with the maintainability of code.
In this course section,
we're going to dive into things we can do beyond naming
things to improve readability
or to hurt it as you will learn,
because this section is about comments
and code formatting,
and it turns out that both can be used to improve our code
or to make it worse.
Therefore, we'll learn that comments are mostly bad,
but I will also explain
which kind of comments would be good.
We will learn that code formatting is important
and how to format our code,
also how to adhere to language conventions.
And of course, again, we'll have examples, demos,
and a challenge for you so that you again,
are able to apply all these concepts, not just in theory,
but also in your own project.