So, what can we say about comments?
Well, just one main thing.
Typically, you wanna avoid them.
Of course, there are a couple of exceptions though,
but indeed, a lot of comments are just bad,
for example because they simply convey
redundant information.
Have a look at this code snippet.
The comments you see here are pretty much redundant.
For example, this comment,
the database engine to what you we wanna connect.
Well, if that's what we have here,
why don't we just name it dbEngine
and use that name in our code instead of dbDriver.
Also, these comments here,
connect to the SQL Driver if driver is set to SQL.
Well, this should be obvious.
If you use proper names, as we now do in this example,
you shouldn't need any explanatory comments
because the names should be self-explanatory already.
And this code reads just fine without comments.
Actually, the comments even make it a bit harder
to understand it because there is extra text to read
and you will probably not skip this text
if you go through the code
because it might contain important information.
So here you have a great example where comments
actually make it harder to understand the code.
Another kind of bad comments would be dividers
or comments that simply mark a block of code.
Again, here's an example from the same file.
I got these big markers here,
which basically just inform the developer
going through this code file
that we're defining a couple of globals
and then a couple of classes.
Well, again, this should be obvious.
I mean, we don't have to tell anyone
that we're defining a couple of classes.
We can tell by the class keyword.
So comments like this also should be redundant.
And if you feel the need for introducing them,
then you might simply have too much code in one file
and you might wanna consider splitting your code
across multiple files instead.
Amongst the worst kinds of comments are misleading comments.
For example, consider this comment here.
We say that we're updating a user,
but actually the name implies that we're inserting a user,
which is not the same as updating.
So what are we doing,
what the comment says or what the name says?
So all of a sudden, a name which was good
now is a name we have to question
and we have to dive into the insert method
to see what it really does.
So that's a great example
where a comment does not help us at all.
If the insert method would really be updating a user,
we, of course, should rename it.
And if we can't rename it,
because it's from some badly written third-party library
or for whatever reason,
then we should at least update the comment
to be something like this where it now really makes it clear
that the comment is right and not the method.
Of course, we should still rename the method
as soon as possible though.
Now, another practice which you see quite often
is commented-out code.
And I will say I myself do comment-out code,
for example in some of my other courses,
to keep it around for reference or to, well, keep it inside
whilst we maybe replace it with new code.
I'm fine with doing that,
but you shouldn't permanently comment-out code.
If you really have code which you don't need anymore,
you should just remove it.
Nowadays, we should be using version control systems
like Git anyways and therefore we can always bring back
deleted code if we really need it.
So don't be afraid of deleting code.
Just do it if you don't need it anymore.
So instead of keeping around code like this,
we should just delete it
and then simply commit this change.
And assuming that we also committed changes
before we deleted it,
we can always go back to these older states
if we need that code again.