Now before we dive dodge into,
a horizontal formatting,
let's also talk about this reading flow again.
Here's another example,
it's a JavaScript file where I call a start function,
which Dennis defined right below it,
so that we can immediately see it.
And that calls a next function,
which is defined right below,
And the same as true for the last function.
Now if would execute this file, it would work.
And I would log all these log messages.
JavaScript is a language which supports this syntax,
we can call a function before it was to find,
because when JavaScript executes,
it automatically pulls all the functions,
in front of the other codes so to say.
On the other hand,
there are other languages like Python,
where does this different.
Here if we would call start in line two,
it wouldn't work.
This code would fail, if we tried to execute it,
because in Python, we can't execute a function,
before it was to find,
it will not magically be pulled on top of the file,
as it was the case with JavaScript.
So executing start in line two, wouldn't work.
However, executing it in line 11 here,
in this example, odds it wouldn't work.
Yes, start would be defined,
but in start, I call next and next,
at this point of time,
when code execution reaches line 11 is still unknown.
Hence the only place where we can call start here,
is after all these functions have been defined,
so that they can call each other successfully.
So here it's really just about,
when we start that function execution,
and then Python simply requires,
that it saw every function,
which is called by some other place in the code,
before it's being called.
And therefore, of course again,
you have to keep such language,
specific rules and restrictions in mind,
when it comes to ordering and executing your functions.