Now we saw all the rules,
we had a look at all the rules,
and I showed you a couple of examples
now it's time for your challenge.
So I had to find a challenge py file
it's therefore written in Python
and this file has some code,
you can execute it
though I would say it would fail,
you can fix it and you'll find
ideas on how to fix it in the code file
but the main priority is not that you fix this file,
that you can execute it, but that you fix
the comments and the formatting in the file.
Not everything is wrong indeed it isn't too bad
but there are a couple of things which can be improved.
And I want you to go through this file have a look
at all the different comments and the formatting
and the code you see here,
and see how you could improve it.
And then of course compare your solution to mine,
so that you also see how I transformed this file.