So here's my approach to refactoring
and to improving this file.
And I wanna start with the comments.
We got a legal comment right here at the start,
and as you learned, legal comments are alright
if we need to add them.
Obviously here, I personally don't need to add it,
but let's assume I am in an organization
where I am required to do that.
Then it's of course fine to keep this around.
Not fine, however,
are these markers here, these dividers.
Yes, these are the imports, but guess what?
I can tell that they are by the fact
that we have to import keyword here.
And that this here is the main code,
well, obviously it is.
It is the only remaining code in the file.
So we should remove these dividers or these markers here.
Now regarding this comment,
this is not a documentation comment,
not a valid documentation comment,
as it should be written in Python.
There, you would use a special syntax with triple quotes,
but that's just a Python thing.
But we actually don't even need it here,
because this comment doesn't make any sense.
It's a class, which allows us to create
an instance of this class.
Well, that is what classes typically do,
so this is a redundant comment and hence,
I will also remove it.
Now, further down,
I got three other comments.
For example, that create directory must be called
before a file is inserted.
This, by the way,
is the reason why executing this file would fail.
You need to call log_storage.create_directory,
before you you call insert file.
But I will remove this for now.
We got a warning here and we learned
that warnings can make sense.
However, we actually got this warning twice,
here and then here.
And if we add this warning, I would argue,
it makes sense in the place where things can fail.
So in this case, insert file.
It's good to know that we should call create directory
before we insert the file.
But what does this annotation add if it
is next to create directory?
This is not what will fail, after all.
Hence, I will remove this comment
and leave this warning,
though of course,
I want to emphasize that the better way of dealing
with this would be to properly handle this scenario.
Data directory does not exist yet.
So for example, to check for its existence
and create it if it's missing,
and only continue if it exists.
Nonetheless, if that's not the case,
we may keep such a warning comment around,
though of course it is also worth knowing
that this comment can only be seen
if we dive into this code base,
not if we just call insert file.
Nonetheless, if we call that and it fails,
and we then dive into the code base,
this warning comment might help us with identifying
the problem a bit quicker.
Now this last comment here is a to-do comment.
And as I said,
adding proper error handling definitely is a good idea here.
You should just do it instead of mentioning
that you should do it,
but mentioning it at least is a good step
in the right direction, so I will leave it here.
And that's it for our comments.
Now let's talk about formatting.
The good thing is we got some vertical spacing here,
so we got the imports, then we got this class,
we got spacing between all these methods,
and that's all good.
And we also have spacing down there,
so that all doesn't look too bad.
Though, we could also remove the spacing down there
and argue that the log storage here is created,
and then we operate on this created log storage.
So we could also keep these two lines together.
In the JavaScript example from before,
that was not the case.
There, we had some spacing between the creation of
the storages and the file insertion,
but I primarily added this,
because I also have this setTimeout function in between.
If that would not be there,
an argument could be made that these lines
should be right after these lines.
Ultimately, that also comes down to your own preference
and to what you think is easier to read.
Here, you can go for either off the two approaches
and hence I will remove the vertical spacing.
Though keeping it also would be absolutely fine.
If we have a look at the methods,
all the spacing looks good to me,
at least the vertical one,
but what about horizontal spacing?
We got no super long lines here
and yet I see some small improvement potentials.
For example, here,
this is not too long, but it could grow over time.
Here we are constructing a file path in the end,
and hence, what we could do
is we could extract it from here
and simply add a new file_path variable
in which we then store this derived file path.
And then we use this variable here.
This would make this line even shorter
and even a bit easier to read.
So I personally am a fan of doing that.
We could do something similar here for this if statement
and extract this, for example,
into a separate variable.
But I think here it is still fine to leave it like this,
but if you extracted it, that is definitely also fine.
Now last but not least,
to fix this file,
we can also call log_storage.create_directory
before we insert a file.
And if we do that,
then I am indeed a fan of re-introducing
the vertical spacing here,
because now we first create a storage
and then we have operations on that created storage.
So you could argue that these
are two different kinds of code,
two different operations.
So re-adding a vertical space here could be fine then.
And that is it.
There wasn't too much to fix,
but I hope it's clear to which aspects
you should pay close attention and how proper formatting,
and good comments can help with keeping
your code readable and maintainable.