So finally let's get started
with our first key pain point
or first area of improvement and that would be names.
In this module, we are going to focus on naming things.
So on assigning good names,
we'll focus on all the nameable things in development,
which would be variables, constants and properties,
functions and methods and of course also classes.
We are going to explore why names matter exactly
and how good names can help us.
We'll then most importantly,
dive into rules and concepts for assigning good names,
and we'll compare these names to bad names
to really see the difference
and of course, as promised,
we'll have plenty of small examples and demos,
and also a challenge for you at the end of this module
to apply what you'll learned.