When it comes to naming things
in development, there is one simple overarching rule,
and that would be that names should be meaningful.
This really is all, this is the core idea.
Whenever you name something,
no matter if that's a variable or a function or a class,
the name should be meaningful.
It should transport what's stored in a variable
or what a function or method does
without having to look at the code
inside of that function or method,
or without exploring the value stored in a variable.
For example, consider this code snippet.
It's not a lot of lines,
but it's really not clear at all what's going on there.
const us equals new MainEntity us process if login,
what are we doing there?
What's this main entity?
What does process do and what is the value of login?
Is it the function for which existence we check?
Is it a Boolean value?
Is it a string, an error or code?
We don't know at all.
And now consider this alternative.
It's the same code, but it's way clearer.
It's now obvious that we are creating a user,
which we are then saving, maybe to a file or to a database.
This might not matter to us,
but we are saving the user
and we got isLoggedIn instead of login,
making it clear that this very likely holds the result
of checking whether that user is logged in or not.
So a Boolean value, true or false.
This is now very readable and very easy to understand,
even though it's the same number of lines.
The only difference is that now we have meaningful names.
So picking good names in your code really matters.
If we have well-named things, variables and so on,
in our code, we allow our readers,
so the people reading our code, to understand that code
without going through all the details,
without diving into it in detail.
Consider these examples.
In all three examples,
it's pretty clear what this code does,
even though we don't know the details.
We don't need to dive into the rest of the code
just to understand these snippets.
That's why names matter.
Now, I will emphasize right away.
We will not always agree, because obviously,
there is more than one way of naming something.
In this course section, I'll explore the rules
we can follow to come up with good names, but ultimately,
you will still always have more than one option.
For example, here, this is readable, I would say.
We are probably creating some admin user,
but this here is also readable and not necessarily worse.
You could definitely find arguments
for either of the two names.
And it's up to you how you wanna name something
in such cases.
There are however, also names which clearly are bad.
And that's what I'll focus on in this course section,
so that by the end of the section,
you have a clear understanding of what makes up a good name
and what makes up a bad name.
And then of course, it's up to you to pick
which good name you wanna go with.