So before we explore any bad
or dirty code, let's dive right in.
How do we name things correctly in our code?
Well, let's differentiate between these three main blocks,
which I outlined
and let's have a look at the different rules.
Variables and constants
and of course, also properties and objects,
which would be in the same category,
are all data containers you could say.
We use them to store some data.
That could be some data entered by a user,
for example, in a web application.
It could be the result of validating that user input.
It could be a list of products,
a single product, anything like that.
Here, for the names of these variables,
constants and properties,
we typically wanna use nouns or short phrases
with adjectives, which describe what's inside
of the data container.
For example, something like userData or just user.
Something like isValid if we store a Boolean.
These would be good names
and we are going to see way more examples
throughout this section.
No worries.
So that's how we wanna name our variables
and constants and properties.
We wanna describe what is being stored in them.
Now, when it comes to functions and methods,
the idea is a different one.
Here, we don't store something in that function,
I mean, there is code inside of it
but that code executes once a function is called
and therefore, in the end,
functions and methods are, of course, commands,
which we can execute on demand
or we calculate values which we return.
So there are commands or calculated values you could say.
For example, we could have a function
which sends data to a server.
We could have a function or method
which validates some user input.
And therefore, for function and method names,
we typically go with verbs
or again, short phrases with adjectives.
So here we could have something like sendData
as a name for the function which sends function
to a server.
Or inputIsValid for the validation function.
Maybe also just isValid.
This would also be okay.
So here we could have the same name
as for the variable on the left
because we wanna describe a value,
which is produced by the function here then.
Though I will say that Booleans
are a special case here.
If we had a function which produces a user object,
for example, we might wanna call that function getUser
or createUser or something like that.
But again, you will see more examples
for these different scenarios throughout this section.
Now, when it comes to naming classes,
it's important to understand
and keep in mind that we use classes in our code
to create things, to create objects.
For example, a user object or a product
or an HTTP request body,
which we wanna parse, something like this.
And therefore, for naming classes,
we also use nouns or short phrases with nouns.
So simply multiple nouns combined with each other.
Something like User or RequestBody,
which would be these multiple nouns being combined.
That's how we wanna use classes.
And if you keep these basic rules in mind,
you've already got a good foundation
for naming your code correctly,
for naming the things in your code correctly.
But of course, we're now also going
to explore the different niche cases, variations
and then also how to pick the best noun
for a given value being stored in a variable, for example.
Because using a noun is just the start.
Of course, you wanna use the best noun,
which best describes what's inside a variable
or what's inside a function and so on.
So that's, of course, what we're going to explore
throughout this section.