Now, before we dive
into the concrete examples,
and the different variations, and so on,
we also have to stop at the important topic of casing.
In programming, we got four main ways of writing our names,
four main casings,
and that would be snake_case, camelCase,
PascalCase, and kebap-case.
Now, snake_case looks like this, is_valid, send_response,
where multiple words are separated with an underscore
and everything is lowercase.
And, for example, you use snake_case a lot in Python.
There, you use it for variable names,
for function names, and for method names.
And that's what you saw in the initial examples
in the first course section already.
Now, Python uses snake_case.
Many other programming languages,
like Java or JavaScript, use camelCase,
which looks like this, isValid, sendResponse.
The same name, but now not with an underscore between words,
but instead there is no separation between words
except for the starting character of the next word in line.
The first character in the name is always a lowercase one,
like the i in isValid and the s in sendResponse,
but then every word in that phrase starts
with an uppercase character, like the uppercase V in Valid
and the uppercase R in Response.
Again, this camelCase notation is used
by many other programming languages,
but it's used for the same things as Python uses snake_case,
and that would be variables, functions, and methods.
Now, another notation which we know is PascalCase.
It looks like this,
and this is used by many programming languages,
for example, by Python, and Java,
and JavaScript for class names.
Class names are typically written in PascalCase.
And when it comes to kebap-case, it looks like this,
and we, for example, know this from HTML,
where we can use it to assign names
to custom HTML elements we might be building.
Now, these are the four main ways of writing things,
and mostly it comes down to conventions
when to use which notation.
I outlined the most important conventions here.
For example, for Python, we use snake_case
for variables, functions, and methods.
And style guides for your favorite programming language
typically tell you which notation to use for what.
I wanna emphasize, of course,
that no matter which casing you use,
the name in the end is always the same,
just the way you write it is different,
and therefore, again, which programming language you choose
does not really have an impact on how to write clean code.
This is just an extra convention you should keep in mind
because, of course, following language-specific conventions
is also a part of writing clean code.