So let's now dig a bit deeper
and let's start with variables, constants, and properties.
How should this be named?
We can differentiate between three main kinds of values
which are being stored in them.
Our values could be objects and this includes lists
or maps or any other more complex data structure.
Our value could be a simple number or string,
or our value could be a boolean.
And you can already tell by the color coding here
that there seems to be a difference
between booleans and the other kinds of values.
Now, if your value,
which you store in a variable constant
or property is an object or an object to like thing
then the name which you assigned to your variable
or property should simply describe the value.
So if you are storing a user object
in your variable, name the variable user.
If you are storing an object which describes a database
and offers database operations
you might wanna name the variable database.
If your value is a number or a string, so some text,
then you also just wanna describe the value.
If you have a variable that holds the name of a user,
you might just wanna call it name.
The same of course if it's a property in a user object.
If you have a variable
or property, which holds an age
you might wanna call it age, just like that.
Now for booleans, there is a special case.
For booleans your name should simply be a question
that can be answered with true or false.
So you might name your variable
something like is active or logged in
because that can be yes or no and therefore true or false.
You are active, or you are not it's an either or choice.
So for a booleans we want this is something naming
or name like logged in,
which also can be answered with yes or no.
Now you might wanna consider providing more details
and more information where it makes sense
but you don't wanna introduce extra redundancy.
For example, if your user in a certain branch
of your code is always an authenticated user,
you could consider naming
that variable authenticated user to make it really clear
to everyone who reads that code
that you're only acting on an authenticated user here.
If it's a customer, you could name it customer
instead of user, to have this more specific name.
If it's a SQL database
you could use that as a name to make it really clear
which kind of database you are working on.
If you store just a first name of a user in a certain field
you might wanna name it first name instead
of just name, to be more specific about the kind
of name being stored in there.
On the apprehend I would argue that age
is already pretty specific.
So you probably can't be more specific there.
So it's not about making your names as long as possible
but just about making them as clear
and as easy to understand as possible.
And sometimes shorter is better.
Sometimes longer is better.
Obviously this is also something which will come
with experience but also with help of the demos
and exercises you will see through out this course.
Now for booleans it's the same.
You can add more details if it makes sense.
For example, if is active refers to a user,
you could name it is active user logged in
on the other hand will typically always refer to a user.
So for example, using user is logged in
instead of just logged in
is longer but not necessarily better.