So now that we know how to name variables,
constants and properties,
let's see more examples
and let's see different variations of names.
For that we will consider what's being stored.
We'll then have a look at bad names,
at okay-ish names and at good names.
And let's start with the good old user object again.
Let's say we have a variable
in which we store a user object.
And the same would be true if it's a constant
or if it's a property.
And let's say that user object is simply the combination
of the name of the user, the email address and the age.
Now what could be bad names here?
Now bad names for this kind of variable
would be something like u or data.
U is simply very short and unspecific
and data is also not very specific.
These variables could contain anything.
It's not clear that they hold some user object.
Names which are okay could be userData,
instead of just data, or person.
The problem with userData is that it
might have some redundant information attached to it.
I mean, if we have a user object,
it's clear that it contains data about that user.
So we probably don't want to name the variable userData.
And for person, that might be too unspecific.
It can make sense.
I will not say that it's always wrong.
But often you might be working on a customer,
or on an author,
or an instructor,
or an administrator.
So maybe you want to use these specific words instead.
If we would not be storing a user object here,
but let's say we would just be collecting data
a user entered in some form and we have a mixture
of the entered values and of validation results
of us validating these inputs,
then we could have a user data variable
which holds this bag of entered values
and validation results.
There, something like that could make more sense
because it would not be the finished user object then,
but some intermediate object between collecting the values
and creating the user.
So that's something to consider.
And I'm bringing this up here just to make it clear
that a name which might be okay in one scenario
might be a good name in another scenario and vice versa.
Just bad names are really often very bad.
So therefore, good names could be user,
or as I just said, something more specific like customer.
User is pretty descriptive and clear
and customer is even more specific,
which often might be the better option
to make it really clear which kind of user that is.
Of course if you have an application
where a user is really just a user
and not necessarily a customer yet,
then there is nothing wrong with going with just user,
which is why it's listed under good names here.
And with that, I got a first little exercise for you.
Let's say we're now validating some user input
and it's the result of this validation
which is being stored in a variable or in a property.
How would you name that?
Pause the video for a second and think about
bad, okay, and good names.
And then we'll have a look at the examples I came up with.
So what could be some bad names for this?
Well again, just using a single character
is pretty much always bad with some rare exceptions.
So we could use v for the validation result.
Or something like val.
The problem with v is that it could be anything.
The problem with val is that we could also think
that it stands for value instead of validation result.
So these are too unspecific and don't tell us anything.
When it comes to okay names,
we could have something like correct or validatedInput.
The problem with these names is that they don't imply
that they hold true or false values.
Correct could be holding any kind of value.
It could be true or false
but it could also be some text or anything else.
And validatedInput could hold the value which was validated
instead of the validation result.
So better options could be isCorrect or isValid,
or something like did validate successfully.
These would be names which are descriptive
and where it's clear that we have a true
or false value stored in there.
Now there will be more examples throughout this course.
But this hopefully gives you a first idea
on how variables, properties and constants may be named.