So how should we name
functions and methods then?
Well, here we can also differentiate
between functions or methods,
which do perform some kind of operation,
and that really can be any kind of operation.
It can be an operation where data
in an object gets changed.
It can be a calculation which returns a value,
but the other kind of function we can have a look at
is a function which computes a boolean specifically.
So which returns a boolean value.
Now for the first case that we have any kind of operation,
the function or method name
should really just describe that operation.
So for example, getUser,
makes it really clear that we're getting some user,
maybe from a database,
response.send
makes it really clear
that we're probably sending the response
on which we execute this method.
Now for the boolean case,
we again wanna answer a true or false question
just as with the properties and variables and constants.
So here as an exception,
our function could not describe the operation,
but instead the result,
and this is really only the case where booleans,
where you wanna do that.
So here your method or your functions
could be named isValid
or something like isPaid method on a purchase.
To return true if that purchase was paid
and false if it wasn't.
Now just as before,
more details are always great
unless they are redundant.
So for example,
if we have a function
which retrieves a user from a database,
but it does so by identifying the user by email,
we could name the function getUserByEmail.
To make it really clear
that it's not fetching a user by ID
or by any arbitrary criteria,
but that it's always to email.
Now for response send
on the other hand,
this already is pretty clear.
Something like response.send response,
simply wouldn't make a lot of sense.
It's clear that we're sending this response.
For booleans just as before,
we can always add more details
if it makes sense.
For example, if we have a function
which validates email addresses specifically,
we could name the function, emailIsValid.
instead of just isValid.
On the other hand again
for a purchase is paid.
This is already pretty clear,
more details could be added in some use cases and scenarios,
but in most scenarios,
it's probably good like this.