So therefore, it's again time
for some specific examples,
now on functions and method names,
again with bad, okay, and good names.
Now, let's say we have a function that saves a user
or saves user data to a database.
How could we name this function or method?
Well, bad names would be something like process or handle.
This is very generic. These could be doing anything.
Yes, it could be processing or handling a user,
but we could also be processing an order,
so this is not telling us anything.
In addition, it's not clear whether process means save
or update or delete.
It could be anything,
so this is definitely very unspecific
and not the naming you wanna use.
Now, when it comes to okay names,
we could have something like save or storeData.
Now, the good thing is that now it's clear
that something is being saved,
but it's still not necessarily clear what is being saved.
Of course, if save is a method on a user object,
then it's way clearer and then save is perfectly fine.
But if you just have a function called save,
which is not called on an object
but which instead for example
receives an object as an argument,
there might be a better name which you can choose.
For example, saveUser or you use what I just said
and you instead make that a method on a user object,
which now again makes it very clear
that it's probably this object which is being saved.
Here, the intent is very clear,
especially if you use the method approach.
And again, just as before,
we are going to see more examples throughout this section.
But before we do that,
it's again time for you to pause this video
and try this on your own.
Let's say we have a function
which validates some user input.
How would you name that?
And by the way,
it doesn't necessarily have to return true or false.
So how would you name this function or this method then?
Well, bad names, again, could be process or now also save.
Validating is not the same as saving.
We might save after validating something,
but first we validate it and there nothing gets saved.
So this is unspecific in the case of process
and even misleading in the case of save.
Now, better names could be validateSave or check.
ValidateSave could imply that we do both,
validation and saving, so it's still not ideal,
but if that is what we do, it's okay.
Check is okay.
It makes it clear that we're checking something,
but it's also not really specific
and it leaves us guessing.
Both names leave us guessing on what's happening exactly.
So better names could be validate
or if true or false is returned isValid.
Validate could be called
if we are not returning true or false,
but if we are for example throwing an error
if the validation fails.
isValid, on the other hand, is a great name
if that function does return true or false.