So now we had a closer look
at naming variables, properties, and functions and methods.
Let's now have a look at naming classes.
Here, we don't really have different cases to consider.
We should always describe the object,
which is created when we instantiate the class.
And that's important.
Keep in mind that classes typically are used
to instantiate something.
You can have static classes with static methods,
but typically you instantiate something
and therefore the class name should reflect
which kind of object gets created.
Hence, classes might be named something like user
or product if they reflect these objects.
You can, as always, provide more details if it makes sense
and doesn't add redundancy.
So your user class could become a customer class,
your product class could become a course class
if your product is an online course.
You can also use more than one word for class names,
but you should avoid redundant suffixes,
like DatabaseManager.
It can be intriguing to sometimes use names like this,
but always consider that classes are typically instantiated
and if you do that,
what is the instance of a DatabaseManager
if that's a person in your company,
the manager who manages all the databases?
It maybe makes sense,
but if it's an abstract thing in your code,
which just manages all the databases your application uses,
there might be a better name available.
Using names like this might make sense
if it's mostly a static class full of utility methods
or anything like that,
but typically, you wanna avoid them
and you wanna go for the clearer names instead,
which can also be instantiated.
And that's really all you gotta know about classes.
They should describe the object,
which is built with help of the class.