So now it's again time for more examples,
this time focused on classes.
And again, we got these three kinds of names
and the question is which kind of object is described?
And let's say that is a user again.
How should the classes be named then?
When it comes to bad names,
we could use something like UEntity or ObjA.
These again are very unspecific.
They could hold anything.
These are not the names you wanna use.
Better names would be something like UserObj or AppUser.
These names are okay,
but actually we have redundant information in there.
Of course, a user is an object.
And of course, a user in our application
is an application user.
So using these names might not make too much sense
unless you have a very good reason for doing that.
Now, good names could be just User
or the more specific kind of user Admin
or also customer and so on.
This is fine and specific enough,
or in the case of Admin, even very specific.
So these are great names to use.
And that, of course, again means that it's now time for you
to practice this.
Again, take the chance to pause the video
and then come up with some names for a database,
which should be described by a class.
So let's say you are creating a class
which then has methods which you can use in your code
for connecting to a database
and for sending queries to that database.
That would be a thing you would definitely have
in a lot of applications.
And the question now is, how could you name such a class?
Here are some bad names.
The problem with these is that Data and DataStorage
are very unspecific or even describing the wrong thing.
DataStorage doesn't have to be a database.
It could also be a file storage or a storage in memory.
So this is very unspecific and even a bit misleading.
Better names could be Db or just Data,
but it's still not 100% specific,
especially Data is almost a bad name
because Data again could be anything.
So this might not even be okay.
Now, good names, on the other hand, are of course Database
or the specific kind of database which is being created.
If you have a SQL database
and your class has all the methods it needs
for interacting with this kind of database,
SQLDatabase, of course, is a great name.