Now of course, no good rule comes
without exceptions.
So all the rules I walked you through over the last lectures
of course apply, but there are a couple
of exceptions you might wanna be aware of.
And you see one right here.
This is a Python code snippet using the date time library,
which is part of the Python standard library.
So it's a built in module shipping together with Python,
which you can use
if you need daytime specific functionality.
Now I'm calling date time now here to get
the current timestamp of today, right at this minute
where this code executes,
and this gives us a date object,
which we then can format to a string
with certain formatting rules
by using strftime method here.
And as you can clearly tell, these names actually violate
what I taught you over the last minutes.
Now is a method as you can tell
by the brackets we are executing it.
It's a method, not a property.
Hence it sounds like a property.
It's not describing a command and it's also not returning
a Boolean where something like is now would be acceptable.
Instead it's just now and not something
like get now or get current timestamp.
No, that's not how it's named.
It's named now.
And since it's a built in library,
you of course can't change it.
This was defined by other people you can't override it.
The strftime method here also has a lot of strange name.
I'm not sure if it sounds like a command
because it's pretty hard to tell what this should be.
I can tell you that strftime should stand
for string from time
because it returns a string from a date time object,
but of course this is really not intuitive,
and therefore, in my opinion, not really a great name.
In addition, even string from time is not really a command,
but again, more like a property name.
Now, again, this is built into Python
or into a python code library,
so you won't be able to change it.
It does not mean that you have to use the same naming
in your code though.
You should try to follow the rules outlined
over the last lectures, unless you have a good reason
for not doing so.
For example, because everyone in your team agrees
that you want to follow a different naming convention.
And of course, naming conventions can also differ
across languages though even in Python,
you typically should not follow the naming you see here
on the date time library because I would argue
it is not super readable.
Now is okay, but strf time, it's totally unintuitive.
You need to hover over debt to understand what it does.
And even that might not be enough,
so you might need to dive into the official docs
to understand what it does.
And if you just explore the available methods here
with auto completion,
you see these methods don't tell you anything.
So it's really not easy to quickly see what you wanna call
to achieve a certain result.
So that just proves my point, that naming matters
and that good names matter.
And I would argue, these are not great names.
And of course, as I said,
there's nothing we can change about it,
but we also don't have to copy it into our code.
Now, speaking of our code,
this code snippet has more to offer
than these built in library method names here.
For example, I defined my own class
and I named it DateUtil.
Now DateUtil is not too far away from this manager pattern,
which I just said a couple of minutes ago
that you shouldn't use.
You should avoid names like database manager, remember?
DateUtil is quite similar,
but actually here it's really an exception.
Naming classes like this DateUtill or also utility
to be even more expressive can make sense,
especially if they mostly contain static methods
like this one does.
A static method of course, is a method
which can be called without instantiating
the class first, like we're doing it down there.
Then the class simply is there
to group related functionality together.
And then adding something like util, utility or even manager
in the class name can make sense to signal
that this will not be instantiated,
but that it's just a grouping of well, utility
or helper methods, like we have it here.
So these are some exceptions and things to be aware of.
Another exception can be seen in this code snippet,
which now is written in TypeScript,
and therefore JavaScript.
Here, I have a database clause which
has a private property client, which is actually set
when the connect method is called.
However, since that property is private,
it can't be accessed from outside the class,
For that we instead have this connected client Getters.
And getters and setters are a special concepts
which exist in multiple programming languages
to provide you as a developer with greater control
over how data in a class can be read or set,
for example, a getter allows us to control access
to certain properties in the class.
In this case, we control whether the client
is initialized before we return it.
And here you will notice that even
though connected client is written like a method,
it has brackets and a function body,
it actually has a name like a property.
It's not get connected client,
but instead just connected client
because actually this getter would be accessed
like a property.
That's just a language feature JavaScript offers,
and many of our programming languages have similar concepts.
So for getters and setters,
it is okay to use property naming rules,
even though it's technically written as a method.
But since we access it as a property,
we should also name it as such.
So that's another exception to be aware of.
However, even with all these exceptions I just showed you,
it should become clear and obvious that these rules,
which I outlined over the last lectures are super important
and apply in the vast majority of cases.