By now we had a look at a couple of rules
that you should consider
when you pick names for your variables,
functions or classes.
There also are a couple of pitfalls you should be aware of,
a couple of errors which are easy to make.
Now here's one thing which I already mentioned,
but it's really important.
Don't include redundant information in names.
userWithNameAndAge is pretty bad
if you create a user like this,
because it's kind of obvious what's in this user.
And if we would wanna stick with this pattern,
we could come up with super long variable names
if that user would not just have a name and age,
but maybe also hobbies, a role, a first and a last name,
and so on, you get the point.
So this is too specific.
Yes, names have the purpose of making us understand code
without diving into the details of a certain implementation,
but that does not mean that we wanna describe everything
with a variable name.
This is too much information which doesn't help us.
In most code snippets,
it's probably enough to quickly understand
that we're storing a user,
not that it's a user with name and age.
If we wanna access that information,
modern IDEs and editors
will give us auto-completion anyways,
and we can also simply expect
certain fields to be in that object
given the fact that it's named user,
it's very likely to have a name after all.
Hence better names here would be just user,
or if we wanna be more specific because it makes sense,
maybe it's a new user, because maybe this code gets executed
in some part of our code
where we are only operating on a newly created user,
and that information might be important.
Or maybe it's a logged in user, and we wanna reflect that,
and we wanna make sure
that everyone reading the code knows
that for this user, you don't need to check
whether he or she is logged in for example.
These could be variations which makes sense,
userWithNameAndAge doesn't make too much sense.
Also avoid slang, unclear abbreviations, and disinformation.
You want avoid slang like this for example.
It might be funny to you,
it might make sense to you,
maybe also to you and your team,
but overall, it's not too helpful.
And if I dive into this project
and I have not been part of the team right from the start,
I don't immediately understand what these methods are doing.
diePlease, for example,
sounds like the product is about to be deleted,
but I can't be 100% sure about that
unless I dive into the code.
So instead, don't use slang,
use objective, clear names,
like remove or sendErrorMessage here.
Unclear abbreviations can also be a big issue.
Consider these examples here,
message n, and then ymdt equals something.
The second line is probably some date snapshot,
but it's hard to reason about it,
it's not clear what is what, at least not immediately.
So here, clear names help a lot.
If we use newUser instead of n,
it's clear that we're sending a message to a new user,
and not to something.
And if we name the variable dateWithTimeZone,
or something like that,
it's also much clearer what's inside of that variable.
Last but not least, disinformation should also be avoided.
And I have seen code like this.
We have all seen code like this.
We maybe even wrote code like this.
What's the problem here?
Well, the first line of code has a variable named userList,
but this isn't a list,
it's a JavaScript object, or close to a Python dictionary.
It's definitely not an array,
there are no square brackets.
allAccounts implies that we have, well,
all accounts,
but instead it looks like we're filtering
for certain accounts.
So by definition,
we probably don't have all accounts,
at least, it's misleading.
So better names would be userMap,
or just user if we store some object or map
in that variable instead of a list.
And filteredAccounts makes more sense than accounts.filter.
Of course, depending on the application we're writing,
we might also be able to replace filteredAccounts
with a better name.
Maybe it's just the user accounts who have a paid plan,
then we could name it, paid accounts,
making it clear for what we're filtering.
But it's all better than allAccounts for sure.
Also make sure that you work with distinctive names.
Let's say you work with some analytics class
which you used to create an analytics object,
and now this class exposes a couple of methods to you,
getDailyData, and you pass a day into the method,
getDayData,
getRawDailyData with a day argument,
getParsedDailyData with a day argument.
What are these things doing?
Don't write code like this.
These methods all sound very familiar.
It's very hard to tell what the different methods do
and which method you wanna use.
And therefore, again,
if you are the person diving into that code
or working with that code,
you have to dive into these methods first
to understand which method you now need to call,
or what could be causing a certain bug.
So instead, use distinctive names like getDailyReport
if this maybe doesn't return the data,
but some PDF or Microsoft Excel report.
getDataForToday makes more sense than getDayData,
because it's clear that it's the data for today.
getRawDailyData make sense,
but now it doesn't clash with the other names,
because the other names are very clear and distinctive now.
So now it's very easy to tell what the different methods do,
and therefore working with this code becomes much easier.
Now the last pitfall, or the last thing,
the last concept to be aware of,
is that you should stay consistent when naming things.
For example, let's say you are writing a function
which retrieves some data, let's say a list of users.
You could name that function, getUsers, fetchUsers,
or retrieveUsers.
They all kind of describe the same thing,
and all three names would be fine.
You can go with either of these options,
but then stick with it, be consistent.
Throughout your entire program, always use the same pattern.
If you went with get_users in one place,
also use get_products in another place,
and don't have fetch_products in one class,
and get_users in another class.
It will not be obvious if these methods
do generally the same thing,
or if there is a key difference between getting and fetching
in your program.
So be consistent and stick to the names you go with.
If you then decide that you don't like the name,
you can always change it,
but it will probably not be the get, fetch or retrieve part
which you don't like, but the part thereafter.
And that's really it.
These are the core rules, the core ideas and concepts,
and the core pitfalls and problems you should be aware of
and you should consider when naming things.
So therefore, let's now dive into a couple of demos,
and of course also, your challenge.