So now that we got all the theory
out of the way, it's time for some demos
and for some bad to good code conversion
which we can do together for the moment,
your challenge will follow.
Now, you'll find
this file attached demo-01-bad-name-examples.py
holding some Python code and you can download it,
you can also run it if you got Python installed
but that is absolutely not something you need to do.
We will only work on the code and try to transform it
from bad code, from dirty code to clean code.
Now what's this program doing?
We are defining some class here, a class named entity.
It has a constructor function.
This is how a constructor function is defined in Python
and this constructor function
receives free main parameters.
The self keyword is a special keyword
and a special parameter in Python
which is basically the same as this keyword
in other programming languages.
So we got free parameters
which are being stored in properties of this class here.
Then we got a function, not a method but a function.
If it would be a method,
it would need to be indented differently,
it's indented like this.
So it's a function outside of the class
which takes an item
and which then in the end accesses various properties
on that item to simply print their values to the console.
Now, the item clearly is an instance of this entity
since we are accessing title description
and there's strange property.
Further down below, I then have a couple of variables
with various values which are being passed
to the entity constructor to construct a item
which the is passed to this output function,
we just had a look at.
So that's what the code does technically.
Now, what is it doing logically?
Whether it looks a little bit like entity in reality
would be some kind of blog post because we have a title,
we have a description and we have something
which is a date in the end, it's the date of today
formatted as such a string, where we simply start
with the year, then the month,
then the day, hours and minutes.
So this year, in this example, it should be a blog post,
hence a better name than entity is blog post describing
what this class will be in which kinds of objects
we can create with that class.
Now what about the parameters we get there?
I think title and description are all right
but what about this ymdhm thing?
This in the end is just the encoded version
of our timestamp here
but this is of course not really understandable
and human readable.
In the end, it is just a date, right?
So maybe we should name it date.
If we knew which kind of data it is,
we could also be more specific.
For example, if this was the date
on which this blog post was published,
we could name it date underscore published for example
or publish date, both would be options
you could go with here.
It always also comes down to your personal preference
to a certain extent.
So I will name it date published
and I'll assume that this is the published date.
So then of course, we need to adjust it here
and here as well.
I wanna use that same name as the property name
and I wanna store the value we receive on that parameter
in that property.
With that, this class doesn't look too bad,
it's now way more descriptive already.
Now what about output?
In the end, this is just outputting the blog post, right?
So maybe we should name it.
Output blog posts or I personally prefer print over output.
So print blog post makes it way clearer
what this function does?
And it's really only good at printing blog posts
because we try to access blog post properties
inside of the function.
So a more generic name like just print data
or anything like that would kind of be deceiving
because it would sound like we can pass any data
into this function when it will actually fail on any data
which has note the structure of a blog post.
Hence I prefer to print blog post name.
We can also rename the argument then and change it
from item to post or blog post, whatever you prefer.
And then of course,
we also need to use that name inside of this function.
Now this is all is a more readable
and we can now focus on the code down there.
Now these names here are pretty much all messed up.
Summary is at best okay-ish but this is the title
of the blog post but don't be just name it title,
this would be way clearer.
Desk of course is an abbreviation.
Actually it is an abbreviation which might be clear
but I personally prefer description.
It doesn't leave our developers guessing
whether that is a description
or maybe some other kinds of texts
but I think desk would have been acceptable.
Nonetheless description is cleaner in my opinion.
Now what about this state.
We are fetching the current date as of today with this code
whether that makes sense or not as a number question
but that's what we're doing here.
Now the name new date is okay,
it is a new date which we are generating
but maybe now or date today
or just today, anything like that might be better
and I will go with now because it makes it clear
that this is the current timestamp as of now,
as of right now.
Here, publish is a bad name.
This sounds like a command
and we definitely don't wanna name our variables
like commands instead as you learned,
variables are data containers
and we wanna describe which kind of data
is in that data container.
Here it's the formatted date in the end,
now is the date and we're formatting it here.
Of course, here I wanna use now therefore
and here we could have the formatted date as a name
because this describes what's inside of this variable,
it's a date and it's not just any date
but actually a formatted date, formatted in a certain way.
Now down here, we previously used entity, the entity class.
This is now the blog post class
so of course here, it's blog post
and we pass into title, the description
and then the formatted date
and it shouldn't be called item of course,
instead, this is a blog post or just a post,
anything like that.
It depends on the context, we can go with just post here
because of the surrounding code,
it's clear that it will be a blog post to be super safe,
you could of course always go with blog post here,
if you wanted to.
And then last but not least here,
we have print blog posts
and we pass the blog posts to this function.
And this is now a cleaner version of that code.
It's definitely not the only way of rewriting that code
and you might come up with names
which you personally prefer over the names I showed here
but you will probably agree that this code
is now way more readable and meaningful and descriptive
and self-explanatory than the code was before.
Now this code which we just wrote,
this code which we transformed from 30 to cleaner
could actually be improved even more
to be even cleaner.
Because the problem we have with this code right now
is that we do have some redundancy or some well,
some aspects to it which I don't totally like.
For example, this print blog post function.
We have a blog posts argument that blog post and the name,
this is kind of redundant but as I explained,
just print data on the other hand would be too unspecific
and it would kind of signal that we can pass
an any data when that's actually not true,
a great way of enhancing this code even more
would be to simply turn this function
into a method of the blog post class
by moving it into the blog post class
which in python's case is done by indenting it.
Now that being a method of that class,
it also needs to receive the self parameter
as a first parameter.
This is just a Python thing
to unlock the self keyword in this method.
And now we can operate on the properties of this class
and we don't rely on some input parameter anymore.
So we can remove that and instead now
simply access self.title, self.description
and here self.date published.
Actually that date name was something I forgot
to replace in the last example anyways.
But now we turn this into a method
and the advantage of this is that now
we can simply call blog post.print
and we can rename this to just print up here
instead of print blog posts
and then call just blog post.print.
And this is now very expressive and descriptive I would say,
it makes it very clear that we are printing that blog post.
So we are outputting data about that blog post
and that's very descriptive and very easy
to understand and read.
So that's one easy way of improving this code even more
and you might find more ways of improving it
but that was one improvement I wanted to make
to also show you that sometimes
it's not just about changing a name
but about changing something in code
which then there after makes naming automatically easier
and more descriptive.
And we'll see more of that later in the course
once we also dive into functions and classes
but this was a first glimpse at something
which sometimes it's the best possible solution,
not messing around with the name
but instead moving it somewhere else in code as we did here,
where we turned this from a regular function
into a method of the blog post class.