Now that we saw many examples,
learned about many rules,
and saw a complete transformation step by step in action
in the last lecture, it's time for your challenge,
time for you to apply what you learned.
And for this attached, you'll find this example code,
again written in Python,
and again you can execute it but you don't have to.
Instead, you should understand what this code does,
and then you should find all the places
where you're not happy with a certain name.
No matter if it's a class name, if it's a variable name,
a function name, a method name, whatever it is.
Now, I will say right away, not all names in here are bad.
There are names which are absolutely fine.
You can still, of course, come up with other names
if you prefer it, but of course most importantly,
you should focus on the bad names
and you should come up with better alternatives.
Once you did that, have a look at my solution video
to see which bad names I identified
and which better names I came up with
so that you get a feeling for how I tackled and solved this.