So in this coord,
we are working with some geometric objects.
We've got a point class, we've got a rectangle class.
At the end of the file, we are calling build_stuff.
We are in the end, we are constructing a point
and a rectangle storing both invariables.
We then return to rectangle here.
Hence, it's getting stored in my rect.
And then I simply print the area of that rectangle,
and I called the end_points method in that rectangle class.
That's what the coord is doing.
And there are a couple of names which are a good,
and a couple of names, which are bad.
Now, good names would be point and rectangle for example.
I'm happy with these class names.
You can always be creative and come up with other names.
But I think these names are pretty straightforward
and there is no need to change them.
If we have a look at this constructor function
in the point class though,
there already are names I'm not so happy about,
and that would be coordX and coordY.
Now the thing is, these names are not horrible.
You can leave them, they are not bad,
but they are also not great,
because they do have a bit of redundant information
attached to them.
If the class is named point
and we do have an X and a Y argument,
it's pretty clear what this stands for.
It's clear that these are some coordinates.
So this coord prefix is really redundant.
We could just use X and Y here instead of coordY and coordX.
There is no reason to keep that around.
So I prefer this, and this is a rear case.
Here, I prefer the shorter version,
the abbreviation so to say,
of a certain name instead of the longer form.
But because X and Y are common knowledge,
it's clear that we have X and Y coordinates,
in a coordinate system.
And because it's in a point class,
I think these names are super clear
and actually more descriptive than the longer names,
since it's less to read.
Now, what about the rectangle?
The class name is fine, in the constructor here again,
I'm not too happy with all those names though.
We got the starting_point and then broad and high.
Now, starting_point could be okay.
This is basically a point in the coordinate system
where the rectangle would be drawn
or where the starting point of that drawing would be.
It's there for okay but I think a better and more concise
term could be origin.
Now again, this up to you,
this is not something you have to replace,
starting_point would be okay, but I prefer origin
because it is a bit more concise.
Now when it comes to broad and high,
I'm absolutely not happy with these names.
Broad and high that is basically slang
or some strange wording, strange language.
It would be more appropriate to use something like width,
and height here.
These are the proper measures,
which we're used to from other areas as well.
Even outside of programming,
we talk about widths and Heights,
not about a couch being broad for example.
So here I wanna go with width instead of broad,
and height instead of high.
This is definitely cleaner.
Now, what about the area here?
This is a method in this rectangle
and typically methods should have a name
that describes the operation, which is performed.
And area is not a command.
It sounds like a property.
Now, property-like names could be fine
if we would be returning a bullion here,
or actually also, if this would be a getter,
which is a special kind of method.
But since neither of the two things is the case here,
I prefer a get area here, because that makes it clear
that we can call this method
to get the area of this rectangle,
which is exactly what's happening.
Of course, here, by the way,
we should also use width and height
since I changed these names up there.
Now, what about the end_points?
In the end this method, is printing a bunch of information
about this rectangle.
It's printing the X and Y coordinates
of the Starting Point.
And then basically it prints where the rectangle ends
on the X-axis and where it ends on the Y-axis.
And we also have these two helper variables here.
First of all, of course, we should make sure
that we also use width and height down there,
since we changed that.
And here we changed starting_point to origin,
so we wanna replace this in all four places as well.
And coordX now is just X, coordY is just Y.
So we also need to adjust these things here.
Now about the naming, we introduce in this method itself,
namely the top right and the bottom left name,
which we introduce here and which we then use down there.
Are these good names?
I would actually say, you can go with them.
You will definitely also be able to find alternatives,
which you personally might prefer,
but these names are pretty descriptive.
It's clear that this is the top right corner
of the rectangle and that this is the bottom left corner.
We could name it top right corner X or something like this,
but this would actually be a bit redundant
since the top right corner naturally only differs
in the X value from the origin.
On the Y axis, it's on the same level as the starting point.
So the x axis, the x value is the only point,
which will be different.
For this of course, you have to keep in mind,
that coordinate systems in programming,
typically start in the top left corner.
And with that, it makes perfect sense
to name this top right, to indicate
that this is the X value, where the rectangle ends.
But again, you definitely also can find alternatives here,
which also could be fine.
However, I will stick to these names
and therefore leave this method as it is.
Now, for the rest of this coord file,
here, we got the build_stuff function.
And as you can imagine, build_stuff is not a great name.
This is slang, and it's totally not clear what it's doing,
unless we look into it.
A better name here would be build_rectangle,
because this is what this function does in the end.
It constructs a new rectangle by first of all,
building the origin point and then building
the rectangle itself and then returning it.
So build_rectangle is a better name
and should also be used down there.
Now, main point is also kind of a bad name.
It's not clear that this will simply be the origin
of the rectangle,
So a better name might be rectangle_origin,
because that is what we plan to do with that point.
It should be the origin of the rectangle.
So let's name it as such, and then use it down there.
Rect is an abbreviation, arguably one which is clear,
and still there is little that speaks against
simply calling this, rectangle.
With that, I'm happy with the function
and we can move down to the last lines.
my_rect of course, is a horrible name.
I mean, what should this be?
Is it the developers rectangle,
the rectangle of the user running this coord?
It doesn't make any sense.
This should just be rectangle.
Or if you had some other more specific version,
like user rectangle,
then of course you should use that name.
But don't use my_rectangle or anything like that.
Also not the_rectangle.
What would that be?
Instead in this case, I'll just go with rectangle.
And then of course, call rectangle.getArea here,
since we renamed this method
and rectangle.end_points, down there.
And actually this brings me back to this method.
One thing I forgot end_points, is a name you could keep,
but we actually are not just printing the end_points
of this rectangle, but also the Starting Point coordinates.
So actually, I personally think
that a name like print_coordinates, is way better.
It also makes it clear that we're printing something,
which end_points doesn't make clear at all.
It does not indicate what's happening.
It's already a bad name
because it's clearly not describing a command.
It sounds like a property.
So print_coordinates is way better.
It makes it clear that this method will simply print
all the key coordinates of this rectangle.
Hence, this the name I'll go with here,
and this is now the name I'll use down there.
And whenever error I spotted here,
which I of course all the one I fix,
here, I have self.height.y, this of course is wrong.
This should be self.origin.y and self.origin.x down there.
And self.origin.y down there.
I had a copy and paste error there.
So now with that, this is the finished coord
and we could now also execute it,
which again, you don't have to do,
but if we do that, we get the area of this rectangle
and we then get the key coordinates.
Hence, this is now the challenge solved.
And of course, you will pretty much certainly have different
names than I do.
This does not mean that your names are wrong.
I just walked you through my names.
And most importantly, for the reasons
why I chose those names.
If those reasons also apply for your names,
if your names also meet the requirements
and fulfill the rules outlined in this section,
they are of course also fine.
Ultimately there will never be
just one single correct name for something.
There are just are a couple of bad names.
As you learned in this section.