Now, I wanna use this course section
to simply summarize what we learned
and give you basically a checklist
for all the rules and concepts we covered
throughout this course,
which you can use to well, keep these things in mind
and follow these rules.
Though I also wanna emphasize again
that you shouldn't really treat it as a checklist.
At least always question all these rules
and concepts because as, for example,
with the functions, you wanna split functions reasonably.
You don't wanna overdo it.
These are guidelines and recommendations,
not hard rules which you have to follow.
Because the most important rule,
which you always should keep in mind
is that when we talk about clean code,
we talk about code,
which is easy to read and understand by humans.
This matters.
We're talking about humans here.
We're not talking
about the computer understanding your code.
It should be easy to read and understand for humans.
And if your code is easy to read and understand,
then it's clean or it's probably easy
to read and understand
because you wrote it in a clean way to be precise.
And there are certain key areas,
and key rules and concepts,
which you can follow to achieve that clean code.
And that would, for example,
be the naming of things,
naming of variables and functions and classes and so on,
comments and formatting,
functions, working with control structures correctly
and working with classes and objects correctly.
These are the areas we covered in this course.
And now let's take a closer look again
at all these areas and let me summarize what matters
for these specific areas
and which general rules you should follow there.
But let's start with naming.
There it all starts with descriptive names.
Describe which data you're storing in a variable
or which task a function is going to execute.
Therefore, typically, use nouns for variables
and properties or short phrases with adjectives.
Use nouns for classes
and verbs for methods
or just as for the variables and properties,
use short phrases.
Be specific and be as specific as possible
but don't be redundant.
So for example, you might name a variable SQL database
instead of just database
but you shouldn't come up with super long variable names,
which takes up the entire screen width.
And definitely avoid slang, unknown abbreviations,
and be consistent with your names.
Don't switch between get data and fetch data.
Be consistent.
And if you follow these rules,
and of course, that's just a summary
of what I taught in the naming module,
if you follow these rules,
you should end up with names
that are easy to read, which is an important part
of writing clean code.
Comments and formatting.
That's another important area.
There you should keep in mind
that most comments are bad
and you should therefore avoid them.
Now, feel free to add the good comments you learned about,
like legal information,
warnings, required explanations, for example,
for regular expressions and todos.
When it comes to formatting,
use vertical formatting
to keep related concepts together
and to separate concepts,
which are not closely related.
And when I say together or separate,
I'm talking about things like adding
or not adding blank lines and line breaks
and also about ordering.
A function should, for example,
come before the function which it calls,
if technically possible.
Now, when we talk about horizontal formatting,
you wanna keep lines short and add line breaks
and split code across multiple lines
to keep it easy to read and understand.
Also use indentation to express relations
between block statements and the code inside of them.
And of course, also keep language-specific style guides,
like the PEP8 style guide for Python in mind.
Also use IDE auto-formatting
and help the IDE can give you in general
when it comes to generating
and writing clean code.
This is all in addition to what you learned in this course,
which did not focus on a specific programming language.
Now, functions are the meat of most programs.
That's where the majority of your logic reside.
And therefore, it's key to write clean functions.
That all starts with the parameters.
Limit the number of function parameters
and try to keep the list short.
Consider using dictionaries or objects
to group multiple parameters into one parameter
and therefore, make sure that functions
are easy to call and the code
where a function does get called
is easy to read and understand.
Now, when we talk about the function body,
clean functions should be small functions
that do just one thing.
Now, you learned that this one thing
is related to the levels of abstraction.
So therefore, always make sure
that there is no big gap
between the level of abstraction implied
by a function name and the actual code
which can be found in the function
and that you're not mixing multiple levels of abstraction
in one function.
Also, of course, don't repeat yourself.
That should be obvious but it is important.
And avoid unexpected side effects.
Side effects are okay
but if they're unexpected,
then a function is not easy to understand
and therefore, it's not written in a clean way.
Now, often you're also going to use control structures
and there one suggestion
is that you're using positive wording
if possible and if it makes sense.
And of course, avoid deep nesting.
For example, by using these guards,
these if checks at the beginning of a function,
which cancel the function execution early
if some condition is not met.
Or avoid deep nesting
by extracting logic and control structures
into separate functions.
That is always something which matters.
Consider using polymorphism and factory functions
to avoid code duplication,
just as I showed it to you throughout this course.
And use real errors instead of synthetic errors,
replicated with if statements.
This also is a key part of writing clean code.
Now, often, you're also going to work with objects.
Of course, especially when using
an object-oriented programming style.
You should be able to differentiate
between real objects and objects
which only hold some data.
You could call these objects data structures
or data containers.
Depending on what you need,
it's okay to use either of these two kinds of objects
but you should not mix them.
Either have real objects with an API of methods
which are exposed or just use data containers.
Mixing them often results in unclean code.
Clean classes also should be small
and you achieve that by focusing on one responsibility,
which does not mean that a class
should only have one method.
That's important and I did explain this
in greater detail in the classes and objects module.
Also follow the Law of Demeter
when working with real objects
since that ensures that you're not diving too deeply
into objects and their API
and the API of only loosely related objects,
which often leads to code,
which would be hard to understand
and hard to maintain.
And speaking of maintainability,
especially when using an object-oriented programming style,
you should follow the SOLID principles.
Now, there especially the SRP and OCP matter,
as I explained in the classes and objects module
but if you follow these principles in general,
you also often will end up with cleaner code automatically
because these principles do not just enforce maintainability
but they also often lead to cleaner code
because they make the code easier to understand.
And these are the main things,
the main rules and concepts you should keep in mind.
You also find this checklist,
which you should really put between quotes
because it's not really a checklist as explained
but you do find it attached
and you also find a PDF document
with a checklist, which you could actually use
as a checklist if you wanted to.
And therefore, you now have all the different core rules
and concepts which you should always keep in mind
when you wanna focus on writing clean code.