Now that we know how to name things
how to format our code
and how to write clean functions
which is super important
we're going to have a look at Control Structures
in this course section
add loops and most importantly, If statements.
Because it turns out that control structures
play an important role when it comes to writing clean code.
To be precise, you wanna avoid code like this.
This kind of code is also sometimes called arrow code
because it looks like an arrow from left to right
and we have deeply nested control structures here.
If statements that contain four loops
which then contain more If statements
which then yet again, contain nested If statements
this is super hard to read, super hard to maintain
error prone and therefore definitely not clean at all.
In this course section we are going to work on this example
and learn different techniques and rules which we can apply
to turn this into cleaner code.
Therefore, specifically in this module
we're going to have a look
at how to avoid deeply nested control structures
like the one you just saw
we're going to have a look at error handling, try/catch
and how to utilize errors in your application
instead of using If statements
and of course as always, and as you just saw already
we're going to do all of that at a concrete example
you're going to see demos and I will also give you a chance
to practice what you learned.
Now I have one warning about this section
this will be a very practical section
we'll have less slides and more refactoring on the code.
This long code what you see here
will change a lot throughout this section.
We'll refactor it a lot
and we'll even refactor our refactoring results
because that is how you write clean code
and I can really show everything we learned
up to this point, including some new concepts
you should be aware of at this concrete example
and I wanna take you with me on that journey
of improving this code.
So if you're not a fan of refactoring
and if you're not a fan of seeing code change a lot,
then A, clean code and writing clean code
will be difficult for you anyways
and B, this section might not be so great for you.
Nonetheless what I will show you is super important
and is how you do actually write clean code.
And this section is less
about tons of new rules and concepts
and more about applying what we already learned
combined with some new rules and concepts.
So therefore, let's dive in.