Now before we dive
into this messy code I showed you
and before we will start cleaning it up,
let me give you an overview over the various techniques
and rules which we have when it comes
to cleaning up controlled structures.
Because of course an important part
of using controlled structures in a clean way
is that you are wide deep nesting.
To achieve this, we can use factory functions
and polymorphism and we'll of course see what exactly
that is and how it helps us,
you can also tweak your naming
or the way you formulate your if checks a little bit
and for example, prefer positive checks over negative checks
because positive checks are typically a bit easier
to understand and you can also utilize errors
and not just see them as a problem
but instead use them in a smart way to get rid
of certain if checks which you don't need actually.
Of course, the composition and polymorphism
and the error part here will also be important tools
when it comes to achieving the main goal
of avoiding deep nesting.
Now these are all concepts we're going to have a look at
throughout this core section but I will actually start
with a different concept, guards.