Now, how can we add a guard here?
Definitely feel free to try this on your own
and for that, of course, you can pause this video
and then try restructuring this code such
that you are using a guard in there
and that you fail fast.
And you should be able to get rid of some nesting
by doing that.
So here's your chance to pause the video.
Thereafter, we'll do that together.
Of course, before you try solving this,
also have a look at the entire code,
so all the code in the code file,
which you'll find attached
so that you get a feeling for what this program does,
which kind of data we're working with.
It's a list of transactions and so on.
And if you're not fluent with JavaScript
and you're not ready to transform this
because you're not sure how to write this in JavaScript,
you should still understand the general idea
of the code and what it's doing in general.
And you can then also, of course,
solve this in theory
and/or by writing down some pseudo code.
So definitely give this a try,
no matter if you write real code or not.
Were you successful?
You can easily add a guard
by converting this if check,
this very first if statement here to the opposite.
What we're doing in this if check
is in the end, we're checking whether transactions
is a thing, so if it's not null to be precise.
And if it is not null,
we check if we have at least one element in there
because transactions seems to be an array.
So therefore, what we can do here
is we can invert this
and we can check if not transactions,
so if this is null,
or if transactions.length is equal to zero.
So if we have no elements.
So if we have transactions at all,
if the entire object is null
or if it's an empty array,
then we make it into this if check.
So now we inverted this conditions.
Instead of having two conditions,
which both have to be met,
we now have a either/or decision
where one condition failing is enough
to make it into this if block.
And all we have to do in there
is then return.
And once we added this,
we can get rid of this if statement here,
which wraps the for loop.
So we can also get rid of it down there.
Now, you see actually here,
we had a else block,
so we did not just return.
So actually we can also put the content,
which was in the else block in there as well
and then return.
We still need to return to avoid
that the rest of the code doesn't run
but if there was extra work,
which we wanted to do in the else case,
we can, of course, do that before we return.
So we log this to the console
and then we return.
And this is a guard which we added,
which already removed one level of nesting
in this big chunk of code down there.
Now, there actually also is a second guard we can extract,
which works a bit differently
and which is harder to spot.
So if you didn't spot that,
that's no problem at all.
That is why we are also doing this together.
But maybe you can see it now.
If you have a look at the rest of the code,
which other guard could we find in there?
A good indicator for a guard
or for a guard being used
is if you have a if statement
with a lot of code inside of it
where you then maybe have a else statement
with some error message
or anything like this.
And we do have this here for this if check
where I check if a given transaction
inside of this loop has a status of OPEN.
If that's the case,
then we do process it, depending on the method
that was used.
We have different functions.
Fictional functions, which are being called.
These functions do exist but they just log something
to the console.
But if the status is not OPEN,
if we don't make it into this if check,
we make it into this else block
and we'll log this to the console.
So this if check could also be replaced
with a guard-like object.
We could add a if check here
and check if the transactions.status is not OPEN.
So again, the idea of a guard
is that we invert the check
and if it's not OPEN,
then in this case, I don't want to return
because I'm still in a loop,
which I wanna continue going through
but I can continue.
And statements like continue and break exist
in most programming languages.
In the context of a loop,
it means stop the current iteration
and continue with the next one.
And that's what I wanna do if I make it
into this guard.
I don't wanna try processing this as a credit card
or PayPal or planned payment or refund.
Instead, I just wanna continue
with the next loop iteration
so that we have a look at the next transaction.
Now, we also printed an error message,
so I will do that first before I continue.
And now we can get rid of the else block here
and we now also remove one extra level of nesting here.
Now, we can have the same logic here
for the refund case.
So here we can also get rid of this
and add our guard instead
and get rid of this else statement down there.
But of course, now that we have the same code
in both these branches for the payment
and the refund, we can also take this guard
and remove it from these nested branches
and instead, list it up to the beginning
of this for loop.
Now we check for this status right at the beginning
of the iteration
and continue with the next transaction in line
if the status is not OPEN.
And continue processing the transaction otherwise.
And that again makes that code already a bit more readable
because we removed one level of nesting here.
Now, of course,
with this transaction.status guard added here,
we should also remove this wrapper if check here
in the payment branch,
just as I did it in the refund branch.
And for the moment, that's it for guards here.
Of course, this is not the final code
and we'll clean it up way more than that
but this is a start.
Now we at least use guards
to make this code a bit more readable.