So now in processTransactions,
we have our guard, we have our for loop.
I wanna keep the for loop here
because after all,
the function is named processTransactions.
So it makes a lot of sense
that we go through all the transactions there
and process them.
But what we do inside OF the for loop
could very well be outsourced.
Not this guard.
I wanna keep it here
because I call continue.
I execute the continue statement here.
And therefore, I wanna keep it close
to the for loop code itself.
But what about this code down there
where we check whether it's a payment
or a refund and then we process the different methods?
Or if it's an invalid transaction type?
This code could definitely be cut
and outsourced into a separate function.
That would already make processTransactions way slimmer.
So therefore, we can add a new function here
and maybe name it processTransaction,
so not Transactions.
That's the function name we have up here
for all the transactions
but inside of the loop,
processTransaction for a single transaction.
Hence here, we get the transaction as our parameter
and I know that the word transaction is everywhere here.
You can go for a different name if that's confusing to you
but I wanna use a name that best describes
what's in that variable or parameter
and it is a transaction after all.
So I will stick to this name.
And then inside of processTransaction,
I will paste in my code here.
Since I used transaction as a parameter name,
this code all still works
because I'm still checking transaction here.
Transaction.type, method and so on.
So this code still works
but now here in the for loop,
after our guard, I can simply call processTransaction
for the given transaction.
And that makes processTransactions way easier to read
and way cleaner.
It's still not as clean as I would want it
but it is way cleaner for sure.
We could now, by the way,
even take our guard here
and extract it from processTransactions,
even though I said I didn't want to do that
but we can do it
because we're going to rewrite it,
and move that into processTransaction at the start
and replace continue with return.
We can do this here
because processTransaction will execute
for every transaction.
And we wanna continue with the next loop iteration
if the transaction.status is not OPEN.
But since I have this as a guard in front
of my checks down there,
if we return here,
this code down there won't execute.
So since this has been there for the only function,
which is being called inside of that loop,
it's the same as continuing
but it's now even cleaner
because now we removed more code from processTransactions
and you could argue
that this is now on the same level of abstraction.
Maybe you would argue that this for loop
is more lower level than calling some other functions
and we could therefore, also extract this code
into another function.
But I personally have problems finding a name,
a good name for this function.
We would have to name it something
like loopThroughtTransactions
and that's essentially the same
as describing what's happening in there
and it's also pretty much the same
as processTransactions.
So finding a new distinctive name for this loop operation
is pretty hard for me.
And I personally would say that this code
is very readable and clean.
So I am fine with keeping this for loop here
in processTransactions for now.
And then just outsourcing all the work
to processTransaction.
The work for the individual transactions
and the work for checking whether this transaction
should be processed in the first place or not.