So at this point,
processTransactions already is pretty readable and slim.
processTransaction, on the other hand is not.
We got our regard here,
but then thereafter, we got all this code.
And the question is,
how can we simplify that,
it will turn out that we can do multiple things
but a first step could still be that we extract
even more functions.
And therefore, of course, as always
through out this section,
feel free to pause the video and try this on your own.
Try to extract more functions,
which would make sense to you
after a short break, which you can use to pause the video
we're going to extract more logic together.
So did you find functions you could extract?
I think one kind of function we could extract
is a function that deals only with payments
and the function that deals only with refunds.
That's something we could do.
So we could add a new function here,
which we name processPayments, for example,
or processPayment, because we're actually
working on a single transaction
where we then get our paymentTransaction
as an argument.
And we could grab this code here,
because we still need to check which method
was used and put that into processPayment.
And because I use paymentTransaction as a name here
I'm going to replace the transaction variable here
with payment transaction.
Now we got this code down there
and therefore here we can call process payment
and forward the transaction.
And obviously we can do the same here
for our average transaction type, for the refunds.
We can cut this and add a new function processRefund.
Here we get our refund transaction as a parameter,
and in the function body.
We have if checks and we work on the refund transaction.
So let's make sure that naming is right now.
We've got process refund and hence,
we can call this here process refund,
for what?
The transaction.
Now here we were logging in the error though
with the addition that we also have a transaction here.
So we don't just have a message
but we also print the transaction, which was the problem.
And here we also have an error though here.
It's just a message.
Now we already have a show error message function.
And we could now just tweak this a little bit
so that it does not just print a message
but all the information about the let's say item
which was responsible for the error and we could deal
for simply print the message and then check if item is set.
So if it's not no, and then also console log,
the item for example.
So that'd be console.log, of the message and the item.
And that's the JavaScript way of doing it.
This check is important
because item might not be set.
For example, when we call a show error message here
then we pass no second argument,
and the offer item would be undefined.
And I don't want a console log undefined.
That's why I first of all,
check whether we have an item and if we do
then we console log it.
And with this tweaked show error message function.
You can use it here to show an error message
and we can also use it down there to show an error message.
And now with that,
processTransaction is way more readable.
But we can certainly extract more,
What about these checks?
They are on a different level of abstraction
than the rest of this function
because we just call our functions here.
And then we have these low level checks.
No, I personally think that's this but
because this is quite straightforward to read.
Nonetheless, you could make the argument
that you want to be extremely clean
and that you deal for one outsource this as well.
Though, keep in mind that you also can reach
a point where you're splitting too much
and this year is definitely on the edge.
Nonetheless, we could add a new function here
where we check.
If the transaction is open and we get to the transaction
as a parameter, and then we return in the body.
The result of checking if transactionStatus
is equal to, 'OPEN'.
And that should be transaction Of course,
this was a mistake I made before as well.
This should be transaction, not transactions
because this ends out of processTransaction.
Now here we can check if a transaction is open
or to be precise, if it's not open
by adding this exclamation mark.
As a side note you might argue
that this is not phrasing this in a positive way done,
but I would argue that the name of the function itself
is phrased positively.
It's isOpen, not is not open.
And then we just add an exclamation mark
which is quite easy to pick up.
Nobody we could definitely rename this to isNotOpen
and change the check in there to get rid
of the exclamation mark here.
And if you find that easier to read,
you could, of course also do that even though
it's not phrased in a positive way.
Now I will go back to not is open though.
Alternatively, you could also name it isClosed.
The problem with that just is
we don't know if the only other status is it being closed.
So we check for does being closed,
if there's also something like white
or anything like that, then this check wouldn't succeed.
So here, I really just want to check
for whether it's open and then not continue
if it's not open.
That's why I'm solving this issue like this.
With that, however, we extracted this logic
and of course we can do the same here
for the payment and the refund.
We can add functions for isPayment,
where we get a transaction and then return
this check and a function for checking if it's a refund.
So here we have isRefund and we get a transaction
and we then simply returned a result of this checkup there.
So return transaction.type equals 'REFUND'.
And then we can just call isPayment here,
and forward the transaction
and isRefund and forward the transaction.
And now we got rid of these mixed levels of abstraction.
And we now got a pretty readable process
transaction function.
Nonetheless, we're not done yet.
It's definitely way cleaner than it was initially.
But what about these two functions?
processPayment and processRefund.
These functions actually have code duplication,
kind of inside of them.
And they also are still not super clean.
You could argue.
So what can we do about them?