Before we're going to explore
how composition and polymorphism might be able to help us
with that problem of duplicated checks
which I outlined over the last lectures,
let's see how utilizing errors can help us
with our code overall,
because one mistake which quite a lot of developers make
is that they don't utilize errors
and throwing custom errors enough.
And errors as well as error handling is really your friend,
because throwing and handling errors in the proper places
can actually replace useless if statements
and lead to more focused functions.
And here's a simple rule.
If something is an error,
if something has an error or a character, make it an error,
don't try to solve it with an if statement.
For example, here is a short snippet,
which we don't have in our big example,
but which you could see in other programs as well.
Here we're checking whether is something is an email,
and if we make it into the safe block,
I do return an object here where I assign some code,
probably some kind of error code and a message.
And then in other parts of our application,
we could check for this object, check the code in there,
and then run code depending on whether we have code 422,
or if we maybe we're successful.
So in the end, what we're doing here,
is we're constructing an error without really using
the built-in error mechanisms
all modern programming language has offer to us.
This here would be a better way of writing this.
We're having the same check,
but now I'm constructing a real error,
building up on the built-in error object,
which also all modern programming languages give you
in some way.
I then add extra data to this error object.
In this case, a code field which I set to 422.
And then I throw this error.
Now this again is JavaScript,
but similar mechanisms for building
and raising your own errors exist
in all programming languages pretty much.
You can always build errors
if you're using built-in error objects,
or building your own ones to add any data
you might need to add, and then you can throw these errors.
And then, and that's the key part,
you can also handle these errors.
And if we come back to our example,
we have a couple of places
where we are doing error like stuff
without really using errors.
For example, here in processTransactions.
Here, we are checking if we have no transactions.
And if that's the case, we're printing the error message.
Now we could argue that from a clean code perspective,
printing the error message should actually not be part
of processing the transactions.
Processing the transactions should really just do that.
Go fruity transactions and do something with them.
Checking whether they are valid would be okay,
but handling the they are not valid case,
that is actually too much.
It would be better to do that in the place
where we call processTransactions,
which is this main method I provided to you right
from the start where we also have some dummy data.
And that's exactly where we can use proper errors,
instead of doing it like this.
Now one naive solution would be,
that we actually return an object here,
where we do what I showed you on the slide.
And we have a code of one, let's say,
which stands for we have an error,
and I then have a message of no transactions provided.
And we return this in the error case.
And then here,
in the the main function
where we call processTransactions,
we get the result back from processTransactions,
so this object, we store it here.
And then we check if result.code is equal to one.
And if that's the case, we know we have an error.
And then we show an error message,
and the message which we do show also comes
from the result and it's that message field.
This is what we could do.
This is how we could handle this
with an error like approach.
And it is better than having the message here,
or the logic to show this message,
here in processTransactions.
But it's bad because we now wrote code
which requires an extra if statement
and which doesn't really utilize the built-in error support.
Hence a better way of doing that
would be to create a proper error in JavaScript.
We can do this by instantiating the error object.
This error constructor also takes
the message as a parameter.
Then here in JavaScript,
we can easily add extra data
by setting a property like this,
even if it didn't exist before and setting this to one,
and then we can throw this error.
Now to have an even cleaner way,
we could also create our own error class,
which extends to built-in error class.
But this is the quick way of doing it,
and I just wanna focus on the general concept here.
So now we can remove this return statement.
Because of the throw key word in JavaScript,
this code execution will stop anyways, as soon as we throw.
So this code down there will not be executed
if we throw an error.
And therefore, this error will then bubble up
throughout our application and we now need to handle it.
That's the other part of working with errors.
And as in so many applications,
we can handle our error by using try catch,
or in Python, for example, it's try except.
There, we catch our error,
and we try processing the transactions,
where we now no longer get back a result.
And instead here when we catch the error,
we show our error message
with this show error message function.
And this is now a proper way of dealing with this.
Now we're using the built-in error mechanism
to ensure that the error message is triggered
in the right function,
and that the error is generated as a real error,
instead of some dummy object.
This is the proper and clean way of doing it.
Use errors where you have errors.