Now, of course, in our demo application here,
we've got two other places
wherein the end we are dealing with errors.
And that's here in processTransaction.
This check where we see whether a transaction
is open or not.
And then in all these processes here,
in all these processes transaction function down there,
we also print an error message
if we have neither a payment,
nor a refund transaction.
So if we have some invalid transaction type.
Again, a better way of handling this
would be to generate a real error
and then treat it somewhere else.
So let's maybe start here in processTransaction.
If the transaction is not open,
then we can create an error,
a new Error with a value of Invalid transaction type.
This is my message.
And then I wanna throw this error.
Here, I don't add a code
because here for this logic,
I don't really need it.
That was just from the example before,
showing you that you could add this code,
even though we also don't use it here, by the way.
We add it but we never use it.
So you could remove it here as well.
We definitely don't need it down there
but now we're throwing an error
instead of handling the error here.
Now, we can do the same here
for processCreditCardTransaction.
And processPayPalTransaction and so on.
Here we can also create an error,
a new Error with this text.
And here we can add some extra data,
for example, the item,
which was responsible for this error,
which is the transaction that caused this.
And then we throw this error.
Now we just have to repeat this code
and all these functions
and as you know, repeating code like this is bad.
So what could we do?
Well, we could again utilize a guard.
We could remove the code from here
and remove this else statement
in all these process functions.
And instead move that here to processTransaction.
Before we actually start triggering processCreditCard,
processPayPal and processPlanTransaction.
We could check whether we do have an invalid transaction
simply by adding an extra guard here.
Here we could check if we have neither a payment
nor a refund
because that is the check we had
in these nested functions before.
And if that's the case,
we wanna generate and throw an error.
So we added a new guard to move some nested logic out
of these nested if statements to a higher level
because we can already perform this check here
and check for whether we have a payment or a refund.
And if neither of the two is the case,
I wanna generate an error.
Now we generate and throw two different errors here
in processTransaction.
The question is where do we now handle them?
And the answer is not here in this error handler,
which we added before
because we must keep in mind that these errors
are thrown for single transactions,
so they should not stop processing all transactions,
they should just stop processing this specific transaction.
Hence we wanna handle the errors here in this for loop.
Here we can add a try catch block
and try processing a transaction
but catch an error if we got it.
And then show an error message here,
forward the error.message
and the error.data or the error.item
was the name I picked.
This maybe undefined for some errors
but that's no problem
because we have a check for this
inside of showErrorMessage.
So now we moved this around
and we're using proper errors for well, working with errors
because that is what we have here.
And doing that instead of using if statements
where we then log something in place
is definitely recommended.