So now we got all this nice error
throwing and error handling code.
I got one last rule
or recommendation related to error handling.
And that is that error handling
actually is typically considered to be one thing.
When we talk about functions doing one thing,
and what's the implication of that for our code?
In the main function at the top
we have all this dummy data
but then here we have our try catch block.
And since this is just dummy data here
we can basically ignore it.
This could also be in the try block
where we then maybe try to fetch it
from a website or anything like that.
So here we in the end have just one thing.
We just have to try catch block inside of this function.
Of course we do something in the try and in the catch case
but that's the entire idea behind try catch.
It's not about not doing anything in here.
It's just about not doing anything
in addition to this try catch block, which is the case here.
But for process transactions, it's different.
Here we validate,
then we have a for loop and then in there
we have try-catch.
So here we are doing more than just error handling.
We are also looping and validating.
Now one way around this could be that we move
try catch actually into process transaction.
So kind of back to where it came from, you could say.
So let me grab this catch block remove the try block so
that if we just have process transaction and the loop again.
And now inside of process transaction,
we could add a try block here
and move validate transactions
as well as all this if code here
into this try block, and then add the catch block
from before with show error message.
This could be one way of fulfilling this rule again
and often ensuring the we do only one thing.
We try validating and then doing this.
And if that fails, we catch the error.
Now having this code in hear is still not super clean
it would probably be cleaner to validate and then
just call another function, which contains this code.
But the question is how would we name this function?
Is this a split which really makes a lot of sense.
We could try it.
And for example, add one other function here,
above user's transaction method maybe
which we name process by method.
And we pass our transaction in there.
And in here we then check for the method
and then dispatch our different process functions.
And now we could call process by method here
and forward the transaction inside of the try block.
And now this is cleaner.
And this down there is also clean.
and that's how I would recommend
that we solve this here though as always
it always comes down to personal preference
and what you find to be clean and readable.
With that however, we're now really done
with all the error handling.
Now I wanna come back to this problem
of our code duplication down there
and how we can maybe solve that in a better way.