Now, we're almost done
with this long practical section here.
There are still minor improvements we could make
and you should consider.
And that would, for example, be that in showErrorMessage,
we sometimes call it with just a message.
And sometimes, of course,
we call it with a message and an item,
which is why we accept both; message and item.
Now, this is okay, we have this if check here,
but we can actually get rid of this pointless if check here
if we simply always console.log the item,
but make sure that the item is never undefined, but instead,
maybe give it a default value of an empty object or a map.
And default parameter values, of course, are also accepted
and supported in many programming languages.
So now we ensure that there always is an item,
even if it's just an empty map,
which we then therefore output here.
So that's a tiny improvement we can make here to get rid
of one extra if check,
because as you saw throughout this section,
getting rid of if checks can really help with readability.