Hi, and welcome to this course.
This course is about writing clean code.
And my name is Maximilian Schwarzmuller
and I will be your instructor in this course.
Now in this course,
I am going to teach you what exactly clean code is,
and why it matters to write clean code.
And I'm also going to teach you how you can write clean code
on your own, which key rules, and concepts, and ideas,
you should keep in mind when it comes to that.
I'm going to explain why all these rules matter,
why you should consider following them,
and I'm going to do all of that with a lot of examples
and demos so that this is not a theoretic course,
but actually a course
with a lot of small snippets and examples.
Because writing clean code matters.
It's clean code which ensures that your code base
is not just alive today where you know it well,
but that it also has a chance of surviving.
Because code written in a clean way
as it turns out is easier to maintain
for you in a couple of months,
but also for your colleagues and team members.
Now that's the course
and all these rules and concepts,
which we're going to dive into
are actually not just my random thoughts
or concepts I came up with,
but instead I went out there
and I gathered all the best practices,
and patterns, and principles, and rules, and ideas,
which I could find, which are related to clean code,
and I compiled them all into this single resource
so that you have one course
which you can take to learn all the key concepts
and rules you should be aware of
when it comes to writing clean code.
Now, this course is full of content,
packed with examples and demos.
And in addition, I also give you a couple of resources
which you can download,
all the slides for the course
and also a mini ebook where you find all the key concepts
and rules in a written form.
So it's not just the videos,
which of course is the main medium of this course,
but it's also this huge PDF document
where you also have all the knowledge to read
in case you prefer that
or simply in addition to the videos.
Now that's the course, that's me,
and that's what you're going to get out of the course.
And therefore of course,
let's dive into the most important question.
What exactly is clean code?