So what exactly is clean code?
Have a look at this example.
Is this clean code?
Probably not.
We can probably all agree
that this is not clean code.
It's a lot of code, hard to read,
a lot of deeply nested control structures.
This doesn't look very clean.
Now consider this example.
Is this clean code?
Well, it's just one line of code
and it looks like we're calling a function,
create, which creates a user named Max
with an age of 31.
Something like this.
Well, let's have a look at the entire code.
This is a Python example
and in case you don't know Python,
I'm defining a function here
and in that function,
the lambda keyword here actually is used
to create more functions,
which are then returned from that function.
So take a pause now,
pause the video and try to understand this code now.
What is this code doing?
So did you pause the video?
Did you try to understand it
and did you understand it?
What we actually have here is a function,
the create function,
which does not create users or anything like that.
Instead, it's a function which creates other functions,
so it's a factory function or a higher-order function,
and these other functions which are being created,
turn out to be validation functions.
We pre-configured them with a certain value,
for example, 31.
And then we get a function,
which we can call thereafter
to compare another value against that created value.
And we either check for that value being smaller
or bigger, depending on whether we chose max or min
as a parameter for creating our validation function.
This is absolutely not clean code
because it was very confusing
and understanding what this code does
will certainly take a couple of moments.
And that always is a good sign for bad code,
if you have to think about it a lot
to understand what it does.
Because there's one thing which clean code certainly is not.
It's not code that just works.
The example I showed you will work
but it's still not clean code
because clean code is not about whether code works or not.
Instead, it's about whether code
is easy to read and understand.
Because it turns out that as a developer,
we spend quite a lot of time reading code,
understanding code, for example,
because we have to go back to code
we wrote in the past to fix a bug
or add a feature,
or because maybe we need to dive into some code written
by a colleague or by some other developer.
So we need to read a lot of code
and therefore, reading code and understanding code
should be easy because if it's hard,
we lose a lot of time and productivity.
And ultimately, entire code bases can die
because no one's able to fully understand the code.
So for example, here's the same example
from before now slightly rewritten.
To be precise, I basically only chose different names.
And now automatically, it becomes cleaner,
it becomes easier to read and understand.
It won't take you as long to understand what's going on here
as it did before.
And we could, of course, also refactor this
in other ways.
We could, for example, also consider creating a class
with good names
and with all the validation logic baked into the class.
Something like this.
And of course, just to make this clear right away,
there will not be a single right way
of writing clean code.
Instead, this is one possible solution.
Using a factory function with better names
would have been another solution.
And in this course,
we're going to dive into many possible solutions
and many different concepts and roles,
which might apply to your specific code and situations.
So what is clean code?
Ultimately, it's code which is readable and understandable.
And therefore, code which is readable and meaningful,
which reduces the cognitive load you have to go through
so that you have less cognitive load
and understanding is easy.
Clean code should be concise
and to the point therefore,
and you'll, for example, wanna avoid unintutive names,
complex nestings or big code blocks.
You, of course, typically wanna follow common best practices
and patterns and also a bunch of concepts
and rules, which I'm going to teach throughout this course
because ultimately, it should be fun
to write and to maintain code
and with clean code, you ensure that maintaining can be fun
because your code can be understood by others.
So clean code is code which is easy to understand.
Dirty code is not easy to understand.
And as a developer, you should therefore,
treat your code like a good story, like an essay.
You are an author.
As a developer, you are the author of your code.
And you wanna write it such
that it's fun and easy to read and understand your code.
That should be your goal
and with this course,
you'll be able to achieve it
because I'm going to teach you a couple of techniques
and rules that help you write cleaner code.