Now all these course sections in this course
will follow a certain structure.
We'll always start by diving into the core problems
and the important rules and concepts you should know
to solve these problems.
For example, when we talk about naming,
I will start by explaining how good names look like
and why they look like this.
So we'll learn about bad code and why it's bad,
and we'll understand these core rules
and concepts you should follow.
But theory alone won't do the trick.
That's why in all these course sections,
I'll back that theory up with demos and examples.
We'll see both bad and good code in action,
and we'll all transform bad code to good codes together
so that we have a realistic example,
and we can see that transformation in action
rather than me just throwing finished examples at you.
In addition, every section will have challenges for you.
There are challenges where you can apply what you learned
and where I challenge you
to analyze and improve and transform some dirty code
on your own.
This ensures that
you don't just learn about these concepts in theory,
but that instead, you get a lot out of this course,
and you will really remember these concepts
so that you can use them in your upcoming projects.