So up to this point,
this hopefully all makes sense.
However, you might be wondering which programming language
we're actually going to use in this course.
In this first example, which we transformed
from dirty code to clean code,
I used Python as a programming language.
And indeed you will need some programming experience
not with Python though, but in general.
It does not matter at all which programming languages
you are using in your projects
and which are courses you are taking,
but you need some basic programming
experience to get the most out of this course.
Because this course will not teach you how to write code.
It will teach you how to write good code.
And that's an important difference.
Now you don't need to be a senior developer or anything
like that, though.
You just need some basic experience.
You should have worked on some projects,
but you don't need five or 10 years of experience,
not at all.
Now let me come back to the programming languages.
In this course, I will mostly use Python
and JavaScript slash TypeScript for the examples.
TypeScript simply is an extension
you could say to JavaScript
it adds strict typing to the JavaScript language.
And these are the two programming languages
I will use for the examples in this course.
Now, even if you don't know these languages,
you will be able to follow along.
You don't need to know them.
I just use them because Python is very popular
and a lot of people know Python.
JavaScript and TypeScript on the other hand
are quite similar to Java and C-sharp
and languages like that.
That's why I wanted to include
these different languages here.
Now, the concepts taught will apply
to all programming languages though.
And if you have that basic experience
which you need, you will be able to follow along
even if you don't know these specific languages.
You don't need to know either of these languages.
If you are a C-sharp,
or a Java, or a Swift, or anything like that developer,
you will still get all the important information
out of this course because the concepts taught
in this course, and the examples shown in this course
apply to all programming languages.
It's not specific to Python, or JavaScript, or TypeScript.
It really applies to all programming languages.
Of course, you should be able to read code
like this and kind of understand it
even if you're not a Python developer,
but given the fact
that you should have basic programming knowledge
that will not be a problem
because no matter if it's Python, Java, JavaScript, C-sharp,
or whatever, the core ideas
and things in programming languages are always the same.
We have clauses, objects, variables, constants, functions.
This is always the same
and therefore the exact programming language as, you know
don't matter, you will get all the important information
out of this course
no matter what your favorite programming language is.