Now I got one other note about
the programming languages we're using in the course
and programming languages and Clean Code in general.
In one of the first examples I showed you,
I used Python.
And here I used Python code,
which does not have any explicitly assigned types.
On the other hand, throughout this course,
you will also see examples written with TypeScript.
And for example, here's a version
of that code example I showed before, written in TypeScript.
Now TypeScript is an extension to JavaScript
and as its name suggests the primary thing which it does,
is that it adds types to JavaScript.
To be precise, explicitly typing things
which you normally don't have a JavaScript.
And you can see type assignments here
in the parameter list of this function,
or also for the parameter of DS returned functions.
Now, there are other languages like Java or C Sharp,
which also embrace the concept of types
and which also knows strict typing
and explicit type assignments.
And then there are other languages
which don't care as much like Python,
or which don't know the concept of strong typing,
for example, JavaScript.
Now, you could think that you need types
to write Clean Code, because having
these extra type assignments certainly
also helps with code understandability.
If you have a look at this code snippet here,
it should be quite straightforward to read and understand.
And whilst the types might help a little bit
with reading and understanding,
they primarily help with avoiding errors,
and only in addition to that,
they can also help with readability.
But the main reason for using strong typing
is that they can help prevent errors.
Because I would argue that this code
is equally easy to read and understand,
even though we don't have strong typing here.
So you don't need to use a language
which knows and uses strong typing
and wants explicit type assignments.
You don't need data to write Clean Code.
And throughout this course, you're also going to see a bunch
of examples written in Python and JavaScript,
which don't use explicit type assignments.
So you don't need data to write Clean Code,
it's not a must have and I just wanted
to emphasize this right away.