Now I got one more thing to say
about the code examples you will see in this course,
just to make sure that we're all on the same page
and there is no confusion.
All these examples which you will find in the course
and there will be many examples are short, focused examples,
always focusing on one specific concept or idea
which I guess makes sense
because that is what the entire course is about.
So these are code snippets and most of them won't execute.
So most of the examples are just small snippets
taken from a bigger fictional project
so you won't be able to run them.
And I just want to make this clear
so that there is no confusion.
I will still show you valid code and all of that
it's just taken out of a bigger project
taken out of context.
And I wanna make that clear and obvious
so that you are not confused
why this code does not execute.
The examples also don't use a particular programming style
or follow a specific paradigm
I'm not doing object-oriented programming in this course
I'm not doing functional programming,
I most of the time have small snippets
with simple functions or classes
and what I teach you will apply
no matter which programming style you are using.
Now, one note for all the Java and C-sharp developers
in JavaScript and in Python
and in a couple of other programming languages as well
you don't have to wrap everything into a class
as you for example have to do it in Java
that's why you will see standalone functions
which are justifying like this without any classes
in all these examples throughout the course.
In Java or a C-sharp these would simply be some methods
to find in some root main class you could say.
So that's just something to be aware of
you simply don't need to have classes around everything
in programming languages like Python or JavaScript.