Now, as I mentioned in the last lecture,
this course does not focus
on a specific programming paradigm.
You can follow along no matter if you wanna do functional,
object oriented or procedural programming or anything else.
Things like naming things correctly
and writing good functions will always apply.
Of course, you still might have paradigm specific patterns,
principles and conventions,
which you should still take into account
even after finishing this course.
So if the style you're using
or also the programming language you're using
has extra style guides or rules,
you should of course still respect these,
even if that's not covered in this course,
because this course focuses on general,
universal clean code rules.
So of course, don't abandon other rules or concepts
which might apply to the style you are using.
Nonetheless, the core principles and rules
which are covered in this course will always apply.
No matter which style or programming language you're using,
it's always about using good, readable and meaningful names.
It's always about having slim and concise functions,
which are easy to read.
And of course, you always want an understandable code flow
and no deeply nested, if, statements.
So this will all always apply,
and therefore the concepts taught
in this course will always apply.