I know we all wanna get started
diving into these sections
where we learn about the different pain points
and their remedies.
However, you still have to be patient
because writing clean code takes time.
It's written over time,
and of course you want to write your best code
right from the beginning.
You're starting a new project,
and especially after taking this course,
you probably want to write to cleanest code possible
right from the start.
The thing just is you will notice
that you will always find ways
of improving your code over time.
You will never write the best possible code
right at the start,
also because your project of course
typically evolves over time.
You don't have a project which you just write once
and where you then never need to go back to your code.
You might need to fix bugs,
you might need to add new features.
And whilst doing that you will change your code
and you might be able to improve your code.
So always question your existing code
and try to improve it.
Refactor a lot because refactoring is your key friend
when it comes to writing clean code.
Because when you write clean code
you typically start on a project,
you plan your project of course,
the data entities you want to use and so on.
But then when you start writing code
you implement feature by feature,
but often you will then find a way
of improving the feature you just worked on,
and hence you refactor it.
Then you continue and you find a way
of improving that last feature you worked on.
And this is a totally normal flow.
Even once you're done with your prototype
or your release candidate,
you should review your code,
and then of course also again, improve it where possible.
So writing clean code is an iterative process
and you're never done with it.
You will always find ways of improving code,
or as you add more features
you might need to change your code
because it doesn't work with that new feature otherwise.
So you should embrace refactoring.
And I know from other courses
that refactoring can be frustrating.
I had students who really complained about the fact
that we did refactoring my courses.
The thing just is
refactoring is a totally normal thing
to do during development
because you save time tomorrow if you refactor today.
If you continuously improve and question your code
you will have better code tomorrow,
which will speed you up tomorrow.
In addition a code base
can really only survive and stay maintainable
if you continuously question and improve and refactor it,
otherwise it will not age well.
As a pro tip,
always try to improve the code
whenever you change something in there.
Even if you change something else,
try to find a place in your code
where you can improve a code,
maybe improve a function
with all the tools
you're going to learn throughout this course,
because this will ensure
that your code base is always healthy.
Because there is a big danger.
I'm of course aware that we're all always under pressure.
There never is time to do it right,
we just have to do it in some way.
And therefore we are inclined to write quick code
instead of good and clean code.
However, consider this example made up plot,
which is not too unrealistic.
If we plot the amount of code output,
so the code we write,
the new features we add to a project,
against the time for which our project exists
in weeks or months or even years,
if we only write dirty code
and we just write code which works
but which isn't really clean,
we'll be able to pump out
a lot of code and features initially,
but over time that will decline
because our code base becomes a burden
and it becomes hard to maintain,
and adding new features and fixing bugs
becomes harder over time.
And this is not some unrealistic made up scenario.
There are lots of projects out there
which had to be rewritten from scratch
at some point of time
because they became unmaintainable
simply because they were not using clean code.
If you are using clean code on the other hand,
you are slower initially
but over time you become more productive
because adding new features is very easy in the future
and you profit and benefit from your clean code.
So that's why writing clean code is key and important
and why it should be a priority
in any project you are going to start.