This course section is about staying clean.
I want to ensure that you're really able
to apply what you learned
and that you can take the next step and write better code
than you maybe did before.
And for that, the most important rule,
which you must not forget.
Clean code is equal to readable and understandable code.
Whatever helps this goal.
So whenever you do something which improves readability
and understandability, it makes your code cleaner.
This is really important to keep in mind.
It's not about checking 10 different rules
which you apply to your code.
It is about writing readable and understandable code.
That is the ultimate goal.
Don't forget this.
Also, don't forget that whilst we didn't focus
on a specific programming paradigm or style
or language in this course,
the rules and concepts taught in this course
will always apply.
You always want to have readable and meaningful names.
You always want to have slim, concise
and clean functions.
And you always want to have an understandable control flow
and no nested if statements.
So this all always applies.
Now, this course didn't focus
on a specific programming paradigm
like object oriented programming,
instead, what you learned, as I just mentioned,
will always apply.
Nonetheless, of course also keep paradigm specific
or programming language specific conventions, style guides,
and rules in mind,
and apply them in combination with what you learn here.
For Python, for example,
follow the PEP 8 aid style guide
so that you follow all the common best practices
for the specific language and style you use.
And then in addition, of course, apply what you learn here
to ensure that you're not just following some style guide,
but that you do everything to write clean code.
Also keep in mind what I said in the first course section
about clean code and patterns and principles.
Not all patterns and principles help you with clean code.
I mean, they will always help to some extent,
but often they focus on giving you a clean architecture
or on keeping your code extensible and maintainable.
And that of course is important, don't get me wrong.
But for clean code,
there are more important principles
and less important principles.
And I had a look at some of the most important principles
throughout this course.
So always also keep that in mind.
Of course you want to follow all the best practices
and principles for your given programming language
or framework,
but for clean code also always keep in mind
that not all principles will automatically
give you clean code.
This is important because it's easy to write bad code,
even though you follow all these principles.