Now, what would be next steps?
In this course, we focused on Clean Code.
And I mentioned in course section one,
that there also is
something called Clean Architecture.
This could be something you wanna dive in next,
but this will then depend
on which programming paradigm you're following
if you are doing object-oriented programming, for example,
and it will depend
on the programming language you chose.
There, you can then dive
into some conventions, patterns,
and ideas to organize your code and your project
such that it is very extensible and maintainable,
and that you have such a clean architecture,
where you, for example,
separate your database access logic from your view logic
or anything like that.
This could be something
which is interesting as well,
in addition to knowing all these clean code rules
covered in this course.
Another possible next step,
or an area you could consider diving in deeper
would be testing and test-driven development.
In this course, I did not focus on testing
or test-driven development at all,
just as mentioned in course section one.
I did, of course,
show that testing does help
with writing clean code, though,
in the functions section,
I showed that you can determine
when to split your functions,
or at least get some help there
when you do write tests because it turns out
that functions which are written in a clean way
and do just one thing are easier to test.
So, therefore, diving deeper into testing,
and maybe even test-driven development
could also be something you wanna do
as a next step.
And you could also argue
that having a suit of working tests,
and that you're testing everything your application does
is a part of having a clean code base overall.
Now, it doesn't directly affect your code,
or at least only to some extent,
as mentioned in the functions section.
But of course, tests have one advantage.
If I read a test, I also understand
what a certain function
or a certain part of your code should do
and how it should be used.
And that's why tests also could help with readability.
Now, testing, of course,
is generally always the same.
But how you write and run your tests then depends
on the programming language you used,
and therefore was not the focus of this course.
Nonetheless, as a next step,
diving deeper into testing
and test-driven development
is definitely something you should consider.