Now. That's it for this course.
I hope you enjoyed it.
I hope you got a lot out of this course.
And I can only encourage you
to keep on learning.
Don't stop here!
Because taking a course is great
- and I got more courses
if you want to dive deeper -
but if you want to master something,
if you want to get
really good at something,
you have to apply what you learned.
You have to use it.
Use it in your day to day projects.
Build demo projects
where you apply what you learned.
Make sure that you don't lose
that knowledge
because taking a course
gives you that solid foundation,
but you only become good at something
if you then use that foundation
to use it
in your day to day work,
in your everyday work, in your projects.
And therefore, I would
of course
love to see you in other courses.
But either way, I wish you
all the best for your future.