This course section will be about classes
and objects and about keeping your classes and objects clean
and working with objects in a clean way.
Now, therefore, of course,
it won't matter to you if you are never, ever working
with classes or objects in your code,
but if you do work with classes and objects in any way,
even if that's not a 100% object oriented style,
then you will get important information
out of this course section.
Because we are going to have a closer look at classes
and objects and we're going to learn
that we can differentiate between real objects,
if we wanna call them like this,
and data structures or data containers
and what that difference is and why it matters,
we'll have a look at a bunch of object oriented principles,
which even help you if you're not following
a 100% object oriented style.
We're going to have a look at the solid principles there
and at the Law of Demeter.
And we're also going to take another look at polymorphism
and see how classes can also help us with that.
It is a concept we already had a look at
in the last course section.
Now we're going to take a look in this section.
Now, this course section we'll still have a couple
of demos and examples,
but it will be a bit more theory than the last sections
because in this section,
we'll have a couple of core principles and guidelines,
which you should be aware of when working with classes.