Now, before we dive into the different aspects
I wanna cover in this section,
let me make one thing very clear.
This course section will not teach you
Object Oriented Programming.
It will not teach you that.
This is not the focus of this section
and not the focus of this overall course.
The idea of this course
is to give you general concepts and rules and ideas,
which you can follow to write Clean Code
no matter how you write your code.
This course is not focused on Object Oriented Programming.
And this section isn't either.
We are going to explore various concepts
which come from the Object Oriented Programming world
and which apply to classes.
But as I mentioned before, this will matter to you
if you're working with classes in any way,
even if you don't build your entire project
in an Object Oriented way.
Therefore we're also not going to dive into all possible
Object Oriented Programming Patterns and Practices.
I am going to cover some important core principles
which you should be aware of,
but this will not be a deep dive
Object Oriented Programming section in general.
That's simply not the idea behind the course.
The idea is to give you all the core tools
you need to write Clean Code.
And for data of course we must not forget
that Clean Code is simply code which is written
such that it's readable and easy to understand by humans.
Now, all of these patterns and principles which exist,
they help you write code
which has maintainable and extensible.
Of course there is a relation to clean Code.
If you follow these patterns and principles,
you tend to end up with Clean Code,
but you could also follow a lot of these principles
and still write bad code.
That's why we definitely focus on the Clean Code part here
instead of covering all possible patterns and principles.
If you are interested in all these patterns and principles
a course focusing on just Object Oriented Programming
is of course the course you wanna take.