You should care about this differentiation
because you can end up writing bad code,
not clean code,
if you mix these concepts.
Let's say you have this database class
which has all the logic for connecting and disconnecting.
You could be using such a class
because you are using an object oriented approach,
or maybe also because you use a procedural programing style
but you still use some classes to hold some of the logic.
Whatever you do,
here you might have this class,
and this class has everything you need
to connect and disconnect.
So you could use it like this,
you could instantiate it,
pass in your connection URL,
pass in this engine,
which you got from somewhere else,
maybe from a third party package,
and you call connect.
And of course,
you can now also call disconnect,
and this would be very clean code.
You would be using this object in a clean way,
and the place where you write this code,
which could be in another method of another object,
would also be very easy to read and understand.
In addition, whenever de-connection
or disconnection logic changes,
you don't need to make any changes in this part here,
you would just make these changes internally in the class.
Now, if you mix the idea of such a real object
and a data structure,
you could for example have a public connection property,
which means that this connection is now available
outside of the class as well.
Hence, somewhere else in your application,
you could decide
that you wanna close your database connection
by accessing the database connection
and then call close on it.
Which in the end is what we're doing here
instead of disconnect in the class as well.
The problem just is the class knows
how to deal with this connection
because it is its main job,
and whenever the logic would change
and close would for example change from close to disconnect
or anything like that,
we would only need to make this change
in that of this one class,
and everywhere where we use it,
this change would automatically be applied
without changing any code.
If we instead dig into our class like this here
and we call close ourselves
somewhere else in our code,
then whenever this logic changes,
we need to change this to disconnect
everywhere in the code
where we used our database class like this.
In addition, even if this never changes,
this is harder to read.
All of a sudden here in this place,
where we're just dealing with a database,
we now also need to understand
how to deal with a connection
in addition to dealing with a database.
This is more to understand,
to keep in mind and to read,
and therefore this is not good code
because of multiple reasons.
And that's why this differentiation matters,
there are times when you just need a data container.
For example, as I mentioned before,
when you pass it as a parameter to another method.
But then, there also are times
where you need a real object which hides its logic away
and where you don't dive into the object
to then mess around with it.
So it is fine to use either of the two concepts,
depending on what you plan to achieve,
but you shouldn't mix them as I'm doing it here
by having this public property
and by exposing some internals to the outside world.
That's why this differentiation matters
and why you should keep this in mind
when you are working with classes or objects
in your applications.