So by now, we learned about the difference
between real objects and data containers,
and we learned that polymorphism is one important aspect
that we can keep in mind when we work with classes
to avoid code duplication and the effort to stay DRY,
which ultimately is a part of writing clean, readable,
and maintainable code.
Now I want to have a closer look at classes in general,
no matter if we use polymorphism or not.
How do you write clean classes in general?
Let's say you're writing some new class
for whichever data entity you might have,
and how should you now write this class?
Well, clean classes should be small
just like functions in the end.
You typically should prefer multiple smaller classes
over a few large classes.
And of course that is very similar
to what we learned about functions.
Clean functions also should be small.
They should be short.
They should be focused on one thing as you'll learn
to ensure that not too many lines
of code are in one function and to ensure
that they are always easy to comprehend and read.
And it's the same here for classes now.
However, there is an important difference
when we define what small means exactly.
With functions, we had the concept
of a function doing one thing.
With classes, we have a related yet different concept.
Classes should have a single responsibility
and there is a principle, a well known principle,
the single responsibility principle,
which actually also revolves around that.
And I will come back to that principle
in just a second again.
The general idea is simply is that a product class,
for example, should be responsible
for product related issues, for example,
changing the name of a product,
not for changing the name of a user for example.
This might sound trivial,
but it is easy to mix up
these different concepts in reality.
Take this dummy online shop class, for example.
All the real code is missing, but you can see the API,
the methods, the surface area of this class here.
And you see, I got three properties here,
orders, offered products, customers,
whichever data would be stored in there, doesn't matter,
the names give us a good idea of what is in there,
and then we have a bunch of methods here
for adding a product,
for creating a customer, and so on.
And all these methods kind of make sense, right?
It's the online shop class after all,
so it makes sense that we can add both a product
as well as add a customer.
But the problem here is not necessarily
the number of methods.
It could make sense to have that many methods in a class,
but the focus of this class,
the responsibility of this class, that's the problem.
Because this class doesn't just have one responsibility.
Instead, this class is dealing with orders,
with products, with customers,
and even there, it's actually having multiple purposes.
It is dealing with updating and adding products
and removing products,
but then it also is responsible for restocking a product,
which is not the same as changing a product name in the end.
So this class has a bunch of responsibilities,
at least three, orders, products, and customers,
but maybe even more than that.
And that would be a problem here.
Even if every method, which just have one line of code,
then this class wouldn't be big when we count lines of code,
but it would be big if we consider its responsibilities.
And a better way to write this code
would be to split this class
into multiple smaller classes, for example.
And this is just one possible split here of course.
Here we could have classes,
which do have separate responsibilities.
Again, you might even be able to split this up further,
but you can already see the idea here.
We have multiple smaller classes where small really means
that we have less responsibilities
in our individual classes.
And this is considered clean code, small focused classes,
where I know that if I want to change something
on the product logic,
I have to go to the product class,
and I don't have to scroll
through the entire large class here
just to find the product specific functions I'm looking for.
That's the idea behind small classes,
and what you should focus on when writing classes.
Keep them small and define small
by looking at their responsibilities.
I absolutely want to highlight that small for classes,
unlike for functions, does not mean do just one thing.
This product class knows how to update
and remove for example, which is definitely more
than one thing, but it's the same responsibility.
The responsibility is to manage the product data
and the product existence.
That's the responsibility here.
And that's a core difference to functions.
And this difference of course makes sense,
because if we would have the same definition
as for functions, then every class would in the end
only be allowed to have exactly one method, right?
And if you create one class per method,
then this is definitely not efficient,
and you would end up with dozens of super tiny classes,
which probably then also would have strange names
just to have one method per class.
This makes no sense at all.
It basically defeats the idea of using classes
in the first place.
So it's not about doing just one thing.
It is about having one responsibility per class.