Now, when we learned about functions
we also learned about these levels of abstraction.
Which in the end helped us decide
whether a function is doing too much.
It was a part of the decision process.
For classes we also have
a related helper concept, you could say.
Which helps us decide
whether a class is too big or too small
in case you're not sure whether that could be the case.
And that concept is called Cohesion.
Now what's cohesion about?
Cohesion in the end just defines
how well the methods of a class
are using the class properties.
So how much are your class methods
using the properties of that class?
That's what makes up cohesion.
And you would have maximum cohesion inside of a class,
if all methods in the class,
each would use all class properties.
So every single method in a class
uses all the class properties.
If that's what you would have
then you would have a highly cohesive object
and you would have maximum cohesion.
Now the opposite would be no cohesion.
That basically means,
that of all the methods in your class,
no method is using any class property.
So all the class properties are not managed by your methods.
Instead they probably are public
and can be used from outside the class.
Then in the end you would just have
a data structure, a container with some utility methods
as it seems, since the methods are not operating
on the properties of the class at all.
Now you definitely wanna avoid
having a class with no cohesion,
unless you wanna have a data container with utility methods.
Otherwise you wanna avoid this.
The goal of course is maximum cohesion,
though this is not entirely true.
The goal is high cohesion.
Because you will never be able
or rarely be able to achieve maximum cohesion.
Instead, you're going to be somewhere in between
and you wanna write highly cohesive classes
where all your methods use many of your properties.
You will not be able to make
every method use every property all the time
but you should have a good usage of properties
in your methods.
For example,
if you have a look at this large class from before again,
I added some comment annotations next to the methods
about which properties these methods
probably would be using.
And I think it's fair to say that
add product, update product, remove product,
get available items and restock product,
probably all only operate on the offered products property.
So they use one of the three properties you got.
Create customer, log-in customer,
these two methods probably only operate on customers
just as the update customer profile method, by the way.
And then we only got make purchase and add order,
which use all three properties probably.
The orders offered products and customers properties.
And refund would probably use customers and orders.
So we can see that only make purchase an add order,
are methods that would really belong
into this kind of a class
because these are the methods which use all the properties.
Refund at least uses two of the properties.
But generally, this class doesn't have a great cohesion
because almost all methods
use only one of the three properties.
So there is no hard rule on when to split.
You can't say if seven out of 10 methods
use at least two or three properties,
then that's good otherwise you should split.
That's not how it works.
But it should be obvious that in this class,
many methods are only using one or at most two
of the available properties.
The majority indeed only uses one property
and that's not cohesive at all.
Now as soon as you start
splitting your classes into smaller classes,
you should see your cohesion grow.
And definitely don't end up
with the one method per class solution,
just because this has maximum cohesion.
As I mentioned on the slide, that's not the goal.
But you should end up with smaller classes
which have good cohesion.
So where most of your methods
use at least a couple of the available properties,
that's the end goal in the end.