Now the Single-Responsibility Principle
in the end says
that classes should have a single responsibility,
and that's, of course,
something we heard about before already.
And that a class shouldn't change
for more than one reason, therefore.
Now, as I said,
we heard about that idea of having a single responsibility
in a class earlier in this module already
when I explained that classes should be small.
And indeed, classes should have a single responsibility.
Now I wanna highlight though
that the Single-Responsibility Principle in the end
focuses on changes made to a class.
But, of course,
that simply means that
if a class would have multiple responsibilities,
there would be multiple reasons for code edits
to be made to this class,
simply because it has well, too many responsibilities.
And therefore, less responsibilities, to be precise,
a single responsibility,
means that code changes have less impact on the class,
and ultimately, of course,
that then also implies
that the class is really focused and small,
which was our overall goal.
Nonetheless, the question, of course, now is,
what exactly is a single responsibility?
Earlier in the course,
or earlier in this module to be precise,
I showed you this big class
with a broad API with a lot of methods.
And I argued that this class
would have multiple responsibilities,
that it would be doing too much,
and I would still say that this is true.
Still, the single responsibility,
as defined by the Single-Responsibility Principle,
is not talking about whether a class
might be doing work on both a product and a customer.
Instead, single responsibility,
in the context of this principle,
is actually meant to refer to different,
you could say business areas, this code might be related to.
And to give you a better example,
consider this report document class,
which actually violates the Single-Responsibility Principle,
even though it's super small.
This class here has a method called generate report
and a second method called create PDF.
Now it's violating the Single-Responsibility Principle
because it's very likely that generating a report,
which is about pulling data, connecting data, and so on,
so which is about generating the final report data
that should be included in the report,
that this kind of task actually
is a totally different feature,
a totally different area in our business organization,
than creating a PDF.
When we talk about creating a PDF,
it's about things like layout,
it's about things like how many pages
and all this presentational logic.
Generate report is way more technical.
It's about pulling in data and connecting the right data,
so it's hopefully clear
that these are two totally different responsibilities.
Generating and connecting and analyzing data
is a different responsibility than presenting data,
and that's what a single responsibility means
in the context of the Single-Responsibility Principle.
For example,
this user class would probably not violate
the Single-Responsibility Principle.
It has a couple of methods, which do quite different things,
but all these methods are related
to managing the authentication and the status of this user.
Be it the user creation as part of the signup method,
or be it the creation of a session when the user logs in,
or be it changing the authentication status
and the permissions when we assign a role.
We could argue that all of that
is related to user authentication
and that probably is one general responsibility.
Now, of course, I'm saying probably,
and you could argue,
because as always this is up for discussion,
and that it depends on your exact use case,
your exact application,
on what exactly a responsibility is and what not.
You also might not always be able to draw a sharp border,
but you should be aware of the general idea
of having only one core responsibility per class.
And you should also be aware
that one responsibility doesn't mean just one method,
as explained earlier.
So what I explained earlier about keeping classes small
and not doing too many things,
having too many responsibilities in a class, still applies.
I just also want to clarify that this does not mean
that you have to split a user
into an authenticated user and an unauthenticated user,
but that instead, for example,
everything related to authentication
might be one responsibility
and therefore might fit into one user class.
So I basically, again,
wanna emphasize that you should definitely
keep your classes small and focused,
but, just as mentioned earlier,
that you should not end up with super small classes
which only have one method each.
Now I did mention that especially,
the Single-Responsibility Principle
and the Open-Closed Principle
help us with writing clean code.
Now in the context of the Single-Responsibility Principle,
which we just had a look at, why would that be the case?
Well, basically for the same reason as before.
The Single-Responsibility Principle,
as mentioned before already, is about keeping classes small,
so restricting classes to one core responsibility
automatically leads to smaller classes,
even if we keep in mind that responsibility
does not mean task, but instead is about a group of task,
which are connected to the same feature or business area.
Still, you will end up with more classes,
if you respect the Single-Responsibility Principle,
and, of course, therefore smaller classes,
if you don't overdo it,
if you don't split your classes too much,
lead to code, which is easier to read,
because you don't have these long classes
with bunch of code in there
where you don't know what these classes are doing
and where you have to scroll a lot.
But instead, you end up with smaller classes,
which typically,
make managing your code and reading your code easier.