Now, besides the
single responsibility principle, there is one other
core principle you should be aware of when working
with classes, especially in the context of clean code,
and that's the open-closed principle.
The open-closed principle says that a clause should be open
for extension, but closed for modification.
Now, what does this mean?
Here is an example.
Now, again, it's just a dummy clause without actual code
because again, it is more about the general architecture
of your classes, the API of your classes
and what we can see is that we have a printer class
which actually has different methods for printing
PDF documents, web documents.
So probably HTML pages and also print page
which may be prints real pages in the real world.
We also have a verified data method which probably is called
internally to verify the data
from any of these print methods here.
Now what's the problem with this class?
It basically needs to grow whenever
we add new functionality.
If we also want to print Word documents
or Microsoft Excel spreadsheets,
we need to add a new method.
Whenever we need to call a new method, besides verify data
from our print methods, we have to add the logic
to all the print methods.
So this printer class might have one responsibility.
It's about printing data and about generating output
but it actually is not closed for modification.
We need to go back to it all the time
whenever we add new functionality,
it's not very extensible and therefore it violates
the open-closed principle because it should be closed
for modification, which this one isn't.
Now this might remind you of this polymorphism example
from before where we had these different
delivery classes for delivering goods
and where we had duplicate code
before we utilized polymorphism.
Indeed, the open-closed principle is kind of
related to that.
Instead of having this printer class here,
it would be preferable to have code like this,
to have, for example, a printer interface,
and then a base class
which just has this verified data method
which probably is shared amongst all classes,
but then all of these specific subclasses implement
this printer interface, which forces them to have
a print method and they extend the base class
to then all have a print method which then just does
different things, depending on which class it is.
The advantages that the base class,
the printer implementation can be closed for modification
at some point.
Once the API is finished, we close it.
Of course we can still edit it if we need to fix bugs
but we don't need to edit it all the time
just to add new features.
Instead to add new features, we extend it.
And that of course is what the open-closed principle says,
a class should be open for extension
and we can build brand new printer subclasses,
like for example, a Word or an Excel printer,
which just extends the printer implementation class
and implements the printer class
which then just forces us to add
a specific print method again.
This is how we can follow the open-closed principle.
Now why does the open-closed principle help us
with clean code?
Or why does it help us with clean code more than maybe
some other principles?
Because this extensibility ensures
small classes automatically because otherwise,
if we don't extend, if we stick to the big,
do it all class instead, then this class,
this printer class keeps on growing and growing
the more ways of printing we add.
On the other hand, if we have multiple smaller classes,
we can add more and more features without getting growing
and growing clauses.
So it helps us with smaller focused classes
and it can help prevent code duplication.
It can help us stay dry.
Don't repeat yourself.
The open-closed principle helps us with that as well,
because just as shown in the polymorphism example,
we have all these classes
and we have wide extra code duplication.
And of course, both aspects, small classes and dry code
are what clean code also is about
because that helps us with readability
and of course also maintainability
but especially the readability and the understandability
of the code is what helps us as humans if we analyze code.
Instead of diving into this large class
and looking for the right method we need,
we can just jump to the specific printer class we need
and it's crystal clear what it does
and all the code in there is crystal clear.
And of course, if we then also follow all the other rules
for the actual code, which is written in there
like for naming and for our methods,
but that is why the open-closed principle matters here.