Now let's conclude the SOLID Principles,
by having a look at the last principle in this list here.
The Dependency Inversion Principle.
What is this principle about?
The Dependency Inversion Principle
says that you should depend upon abstractions
not concretions.
And that's a super fancy term, which I don't know about you,
but which might be totally unclear.
At least this sentence was totally unclear to me,
when I first read it.
It is however not even close
as complex and complicated as it sounds.
And if you are following the other principles already,
then chances are pretty high
that you're already following this one as well,
or at least that it's very easy to follow this one as well.
Now here I got another example,
which actually is very close
to the Interface Segregation Principle,
we covered in the last lecture.
Following the Interface Segregation Principle,
I got two interfaces here,
Database and Remote Database Interface.
And then I got two classes,
the SQL database class and the In-memory database class,
which actually use these Interfaces.
Now, I also got an app class down there,
where I actually need a database
as agreement in the constructor.
And that database either has to be a SQL database,
or an In-memory database.
This app works with both.
But depending on what it is,
I have to run the connect method as part of my constructor.
That's why I have this if-check here.
The problem with this example,
is that we depend on concretions.
I depend on the concrete implementation of my database.
I accept both types here,
and therefore I have to check which type I'm getting,
so that I can execute this extra code,
which I might need to execute.
Now, it shouldn't be needless to say
that code like this can be hard to maintain,
because the more types of databases we add,
the more if-checks we might need to add here,
and whenever the connect method changes
we also need to change it in all the places
where we do have a check like this
and where we do call connect.
So therefore this could become a problem
in bigger applications where you maybe also have
different kinds of databases.
Now we can change the code
to follow the Dependency Inversion Principle though,
and changing it will be very simple
because I'm already following
the Interface Segregation Principle here
by having my different interfaces.
These interfaces in the end are abstractions.
I can use these interfaces to buy certain functionalities
to ensure certain functionalities
without knowing how exactly they work under the hood.
But I can rely on the fact that for example
a connect method or a store data method is there.
And then here in this app, we could say
that in the end all we want is a database.
I don't wanna deal with connecting here.
I just want to ensure that the type of database I have here
the type of disagreement is of type database.
So it should be a class
which implements the database interface.
And the database interface
in the end just ensures that there is a store data method,
not that there is a connect method.
So therefore of course, we should remove this if-check
because we know we got a database
which only has a store data method
and we don't have a connect method here.
Instead it's now the place where we create our app
where we have to provide a database
as expected by this class.
And that's why it's called
the Dependency Inversion Principle.
We no longer care about the data here in the app class.
So in the consuming class, we don't wanna check
which kind of data we got here.
Instead, we invert the dependency
and we don't depend on the type of database,
but instead we force whoever is instantiating that class
to provide us a database which will fulfills this contract.
And just this contract.
So wherever we are instantiating the app class
we now need to pass in a new database.
And therefore it's now here in this place
where I for example need to create a new SQL database
and also call connect here.
Because that's now my responsibility here in this place.
The app doesn't care about it
because it inverted the dependencies.
It tells me to provide a proper value.
It doesn't want to check it internally.
And this tends to be more maintainable
because you can even use
Dependency Injection frameworks and approaches
to have only a few places in your application
where things are created.
So where for example, this database is created and connected
and to have many places in your app
where you then depend on this abstract database.
That's the idea of the Dependency Inversion Principle.
And that's how you write code that follows this principle.
Now, of course like all these principles
there also is a connection to Clean Code here.
By inverting the dependency,
of course we reduce the amount of code we have in here
and that of course automatically makes this
smaller more readable and avoids code duplication.
So it certainly matters.
But the Dependency Inversion Principle
is also kind of a result
or at least strongly related to the other principles.
And in addition the key benefit
definitely is maintainability and extensibility.
So of course it matters, all of these principles matter
but I would argue it's not as important
as the first two principles, which were covered.
The Single Responsibility
and the Open-Closed Principle.
Nonetheless, we now had a look at all these SOLID principles
which are popular for a good reason.
And if you are working with classes
and especially if you are following
Project Oriented approach,
if you are writing code in an object oriented way
you should also consider and respect these principles
because ultimately they will lead
to more maintainable and extensible code.
And as a great side effect,
they also tend to give you Cleaner Code.