By now in this course,
we learned how to name things properly
and to not overuse comments.
We haven't worked too much on the actual code
which we write except for the names
we assigned two things.
Now therefore in this course section,
we are going to take a closer look at functions
because functions ultimately are where we write
the majority of our code, functions or methods.
And in this course section,
you will learn how to write clean functions
and we'll have a look at every aspect of functions.
We'll have a look at the parameters,
the arguments you use
and functions and how to be clean there.
And of course, we're going to have a look
at the function body,
and we're going to talk about the length of functions,
abstraction levels and how to properly split one function
into multiple functions to increase readability.
And as always, we're going to do this
with a bunch of examples, demos
and also a challenge for you.
So let's dive in.