Now, let's start with the left side here
with calling a function and with passing values
for function parameters.
And here for writing clean code
and for being able to call functions in a clean
and understandable way, there is one simple rule,
you should minimize the number of parameters
your functions use.
Because the more parameters a function uses,
the harder it gets to call them.
And harder here really means that it's harder to memorize
which values should be passed as which argument.
So the order of arguments can be confusing.
And if you have to pass in a lot of arguments,
it all is as simply as a lot of code to write
and ultimately that all leads to more code you have to read
more things you have to keep in mind.
We can probably all agree that calling a function
or method with no parameters is very simple.
If we, for example, have a user object
and on that user object we have a safe method,
then this is very easy to call and to read.
We don't have to pass in multiple values
and remember the order of arguments,
we don't have to do anything of debt.
We have one function call with no parameters
this therefore is very easy to understand.
So it's easy to understand and easy to call.
And therefore, this is the best possible way
of calling a function though of course,
I will say right away,
this is not always the way you can do it.
There are of course functions or methods
which do require parameters.
You can't refactor every function to take no parameters.
That will just not be an option.
Nonetheless, sometimes you can achieve this.
And if you can, this therefore is the best possible option
when it comes to ease of calling
and to understanding this code.
Still very good, is if you need one parameter, one argument.
For example, if you had a log function,
which takes the message as to one argument at once.
This is still very easy to understand
and still very easy to call.
You have to pass in one value.
There is no order, which you have to memorize.
And if you read this code, it's crystal clear what it does.
So this is still a very good option you can use.
Now, it already becomes a bit more tricky
if you have two arguments, two parameters,
which need to be passed in.
For example, if we have a point object,
which we can instantiate by calling its constructor,
which this code could do
where we then pass in two arguments.
Let's say the X and Y coordinate of that point.
This is still okay to understand,
because it is kind of common sense that probably the X value
is the first argument
and the Y value is the second argument,
but still there is some ordering,
which you need to keep in mind.
The order could be switched
and therefore this acceptable to call,
but you might have to think about it for a second
to quickly verify that the first value
really is the X value and the second value is the Y value.
So therefore, you should use this approach
or write functions with more than one argument with caution.
In some cases like here, for a point,
it is still absolutely fine because it is quite obvious
that the first value will be the X value
and the second value will be the Y value,
but for other functions, this might not be as clear.
And then it immediately becomes harder to call them
because you have to think about the order of arguments.
And reading that code, therefore, also could become harder
because it's not immediately obvious
which argument fulfills which purpose.
Now, if we have even more arguments,
let's say three arguments, then we reach the point
where it's very hard to justify
why we need that many arguments.
For example, if we have a calc function,
which calculates something,
we might take in the two numbers
which we wanna use in the calculation
and then we have a third parameter
which defines which kind of calculation we wanna perform.
And this is challenging to understand
and challenging to call.
If we read this, it is still okay if we have add as a type,
but if we have subtract, it's already not 100% clear,
which number gets subtracted from which other number.
But especially when we call this
it's also hard to understand
because the order is totally not obvious.
We will probably need to dive into the code
or use some IDE features
to understand which arguments should go where.
For example, the type of calculation and in this example
could also be the first argument.
Common sense doesn't tell us whether it should be the last
or the first argument,
because this is not a common function,
not a common thing, unlike the point.
So therefore, you wanna avoid functions
like this if possible.
There can always be scenarios
where you need a function like this,
but you will probably not have them as often
as the other scenarios on the left here
for none, one and two arguments.
Now, any functions with more than three arguments
should absolutely be avoided.
For example, if you had a coords function,
which takes four values,
this would be very difficult to understand and to read
and very difficult to call.
It's not obvious at all, which value describes
which coordinate or what this function really does or wants.
So you really always wanna avoid having functions
with more than free arguments.
Nonetheless, I could imagine that you now automatically
have a couple of examples in mind where you think,
well, but I need more than two pieces of data
or more than three pieces of data.
So let's now have a look at a couple of examples
and a couple of solutions
for functions which need more than three pieces of data.