Now, we will dive into the functions
which are a bit harder to understand.
For example, this example.
We have a User class with a constructor function,
where we assign name, age, and email.
Now, this can be instantiated like this.
And if we read this code, it is kind of obvious
that it's the name, the age, and the email address.
If we write this code, however,
our IDE will definitely give us some help.
So it's not too hard to fill this out,
but it is not 100% obvious in general
that the name field will be the first argument,
then the age, and then the email address.
This is not something we can take for granted.
It would not be unexpected
if the email field would be first,
and therefore it's not too hard to call this,
because of this IDE support, but it might be even better
if we don't need that IDE support like this at all,
if we don't constantly have to look
at which value goes where.
And therefore, to actually improve the readability
and usability of this function,
which a constructor function still is in the end,
we could rewrite this example like this.
Here, we have our User class still,
but now it doesn't take three arguments
in the constructor, but just one.
But that one argument is a simple data container,
an object or a map, which has various fields
which we then use to extract the values
for name, age, and email,
but now the advantage is that when we call this function,
when we instantiate this class down here,
we just pass in such a object here in JavaScript,
a hash map or a dictionary in other languages,
and the order does now totally not matter.
It doesn't matter if we have name, email, age here
or email, age, name
because we now extract the values by identifier name,
by key in the end, like we're doing it here.
So now, we don't have to worry about the order anymore.
And if we see this code, it's all the even more readable.
It's now 100% obvious that Max is the name
and not, for example, just the first name,
which is something we could have thought
with this first example here.
It's not clear whether that is the username,
the full name, or the first name.
Here, it's clear. It's the name in general.
So the username probably.
And therefore, this is how we could replace
multiple parameters with one parameter
by simply using an object or a map as that one parameter.
That allows us to technically still feed in
more than one value, but in a more structured way.
And this is therefore your go-to solution
if you have a function which needs multiple pieces of data,
which is totally normal, but where at the same time,
you don't want to have an endless
or unstructured list of arguments.
Then, you can simply refactor this to just use one argument,
which then in turn is a structured data container,
like a map or an object.
Here's a similar example.
I have this compare function,
which takes two values and then the comparator argument,
which in the end defines which kind of comparison is made.
And, again, this is very hard to call.
It's not obvious whether that comparator
should be the first or the last value,
and hence, this function could also be rewritten like this.
Now, it takes just one argument,
which again is such a object or map of key value pairs,
where it's now much easier to identify
what the first and second value is
and which kind of comparison operation is being performed.
And, again, the order does not matter here.
We could also have comparator here
as a first key value pair
because it's all in the same single argument.
It's just a map and object here
where this data is grouped together,
and in there, the order does not matter at all
because we extract the values by key anyways.
So that is how we could avoid having functions
with three or more arguments.
Because whilst three arguments can be acceptable
in rare cases, it's almost always the case
that rewriting it like this is way easier
to grasp and understand.