Now when it comes to the number of parameters
there is one special case, one special scenario.
And that would be functions like this.
Sum Up function, which simply sums up all the values
we pass in.
We can have functions like this
and even though this function takes six parameters,
six arguments in this case,
I would argue that it's very easy to read and understand.
It's very clear what this function does
and the order does actually not matter here
even for this example.
Still technically we violate the rule
of having less than or equal to three parameters.
Here we have six.
Now of course we could rewrite this function
also internally of course, to take an array as the argument.
Then we technically have only one argument
because this is one array.
Please note the square brackets.
We could do this
and this could be a perfectly viable solution,
but we don't even have to do that.
So here I'll comment that out
so that we still have it for reference.
Otherwise of course we learned
that we shouldn't comment out things but simply delete them.
Nonetheless, here I'm doing it so that we still have
this alternative solution for comparison,
but I still wanna make a point.
That this way of doing it also can be absolutely fine
because most programming languages allow you
to take in a dynamic number of arguments
and they then have a certain Syntax
for grouping all these arguments together
into an array inside of that function.
For example here in JavaScript,
it's this three-dot operator here.
Which simply tells JavaScript
that numbers can be any number of parameters,
any number of values,
but that they will all be merged together into one array.
Which is why, then we can simply loop through that array
to do something with the values in there.
And that allows us to define a function
which technically takes more than one parameter
and more than three parameters even,
but which still is very readable
and internally simply uses an array.
And I would argue that functions like this
also are pretty clean because ultimately we must not forget
that clean code is not about hard rules
which you have to follow under all circumstances,
but that it's about writing code which is understandable,
easy to read and easy to maintain.
And if this code is perfectly easy to read and maintain,
hence there is nothing wrong with it.