Now that we had an extensive look
at the function parameters and arguments,
let's have a closer look at the function body
because when we talk about clean functions
and writing clean functions,
obviously, the function body
is an important part of that.
We wanna write functions where the body of functions,
which makes up the majority of the function code
is written in a clean way.
And how do we ensure that our function body,
so to code inside of a function is clean?
Well, functions should be small.
They should be really small
because if a function is small
it's easier to read and understand than if it's big,
if it contains a lot of code.
Consider this example here,
you're all to find this file attached to this lecture.
This is one function
with quite a lot of code inside of it.
Now, pause the video at this point,
and to take a moment to understand
or to try to understand
what this function does
or to at least get an idea
of what this function could do.
It's again, of course,
just a snippet.
It's just a dummy example,
but it does fulfill a real purpose.
So, take a moment to pause
and find out what this function does.
Were you successful?
Did you find out what this function is doing,
or do you at least have
a rough idea of what this function is doing?
It's certainly not impossible to find out,
but it will take you a couple of moments, right?
You will definitely not look at this function
and instantly see what it does in detail.
Now, I can tell you what this function does.
It's a dummy function that could render some HTML content.
And for this it first of all,
checks the input and ensures
that no script element is being rendered.
And if it is,
then we throw in the error.
Thereafter, the HTML tags are constructed
by building a opening and a closing tag.
And the opening tag is actually constructed
by also adding any attributes
which should be added on that HTML element.
And then it constructs a template
where opening and closing tag
are combined with the actual content of that element,
so the part between the tags
and then that template is in the end
attached to some root element,
which we get as a parameter.
And this root element therefore,
actually is kind of an output parameter here,
but let's ignore this for a moment here,
because of course there can be scenarios
where this is acceptable.
And in general, this function here
uses good naming,
good formatting,
that's all fine.
And still it's not clean
because it takes quite some time
to understand what's going on.
Now, here's an alternative version of that function.
Now, many parts of that function code
were outsourced into separate functions
and therefore the main function,
renderContent is pretty lean.
And if I were to tell you to understand
what this function does,
you would probably be able to understand this
way quicker than with the example I gave you before,
even though the function produces the same result.
But by splitting the code
into multiple more focused functions,
this main function
is easier to understand.
And also all these extracted functions on their own
will be quite easy to understand.
It's pretty easy to see
and it doesn't take long to understand
that when renderContent is called,
we validate the element type
because the function is even called like that,
then we create the renderable content,
so the content which would be output,
and then we render that on some root element
with the render on root function.
Now, as I mentioned,
this code was split across multiple functions
and this can look intimidating
because it overall grew of course,
but each of these functions is quite straightforward
and easy to understand.
And the idea of writing clean code
is precisely that you don't have to read
all the related code.
If I need to look just at renderContent,
I typically don't need to dive
into all these outsourced functions.
So I might not even see all that other code.
And therefore, if I just consider renderContent,
that is way easier to understand
than at the example before.
And even if I do need to dive
into the individual functions thereafter,
all these functions are all the written such
that they are quite focused and straightforward,
and should be relatively easy to understand.
And that's why clean functions should be small.
And we achieve this
by splitting functions into multiple functions.
Now, one question you might be asking yourself now
is how did I decide
what to outsource
and which code to put into separate functions?
And here we have a simple rule,
to write small functions
we should write functions
that do exactly one thing.
But of course that brings up a new question.
What is
one thing?
Because if you have a look at this refactored example,
it's easy to argue
that this function is doing more than one thing.
It's validating the element type,
creating renderable content
and rendering this on a root element.
You could argue that these are
three things and not just one thing.
Now, of course, in programming,
it's quite common
that we have functions
that kick off multiple operations.
The goal is not to write functions
where every function has just one line of code.
That's unrealistic and also not helpful.
You don't wanna clutter your code
with millions of functions.
Instead, one thing
is defined slightly different.
When we talk about functions doing one thing
we could think about the different operations
a function is doing,
like validating and saving user input, for example.
And then we could argue that we have two operations
and that's of course similar
to the actual example I showed you a second ago.
But we don't look at the different operations.
Instead, we combine the idea of doing one thing
with the concept of levels of abstraction.
This concept of looking at the levels of abstraction
of the operations inside of a function,
this concept helps us decide
when to split a function into multiple functions.
Here's an example,
email includes @ and saveUser.
If we have a look at these two code snippets,
then email includes
is a pretty low level API operation on a string.
In JavaScript,
it's a built-in method,
which we can call on strings
to check if a string
contains a certain character or text.
saveUser on the other hand
is pretty high level.
It's a developer defined function for saving a user.
We're not using some low level built-in API here.
That's what levels of abstraction are about.
We got high and low levels of abstraction
and a broad band with in between.
And high level operations would be operations
where we just called some function or method,
which has a descriptive name
and then does something.
Now, a low level operation, on the other hand,
really dives into the low level API methods
or operations, a certain programming language
or framework offers.
In the case of isEmail,
there's higher level operation here.
We don't control how the email is validated,
we don't know what is actually going on in there,
we just want the email to be validated.
We're just interested in the result.
Now, with the low level example
we do control how the email is validated.
This is the concrete code
which decides whether something is valid or not.
But the interesting thing is that with the low level example
it's not even clear that we're talking about
email validation.
Includes is a method we can call on any string.
We, as a developer, add extra meaning
by interpreting the result.
If I call includes @ on an email,
sure, I wanna validate whether that is an email,
but that's some extra meaning I, as a developer,
add to this operation.
It's not obvious by the operation or the method name itself.
Includes is a name which does not imply any meaning
other than that a string includes a certain character.
isEmail on the other hand,
is easy to read and there is no room for interpretation.
If I call a function called isEmail,
it's clear that I wanna find out
if something is an email or not.
I wanna get back true or false here.
Now for includes @, it's technically clear
that it checks for the existence of a @ symbol
in some string,
but the interpretation
that this means that a email address is valid
is something which must be added by the reader.
That's why this is lower level.
We have to add the meaning to that.
For higher level operations,
the meaning is baked into the operation so to say.
So that's the general difference
between higher level and lower level operations.
In one case you just know the result,
you just know which task should be executed,
in the low level case,
you know the actual work that's being done
and it's your job to understand
why this work is being done
and what the goal of that is.
Now, the message here is not
that you should write high level code only.
Low level code can also be quite understandable
if you write it in the right place.
And that's what we're going to dive in next.
Why exactly do these levels of abstraction matter
and when should you write which code?