I introduced this concept
of levels of abstraction in the last lecture,
because the levels of abstraction allow us to decide
whether a function does one thing
or if it does multiple things.
Because functions should only do work
that's one level of abstraction
below the level of abstraction
implied by their function name.
Okay, that's a complex sentence.
What does it mean?
Consider this example.
If you have function which is called emailIsValid,
and it takes an email as a parameter,
then you might have some low level of code in there,
as you can tell in this example.
But, this operation is one level below
the function name implied level.
EmailIsValid, if we would call this function,
is pretty highlevel,
but it's clear that as a result,
we want to know whether an email is valid or not.
So inside of that emailIsValid function,
we perform an operation on a lower level of abstraction.
In this case, email includes @.
But writing this low level code here is no problem,
because understanding it is quite easy,
because of the function name,
of the function in which we write it.
The function is named emailIsValid,
so it's clear that we're doing this low level work
to get an answer to this question.
So, because the operation we do inside of
the function is close to the level of abstraction implied
by the function name,
because it answers the question posed by the function name,
we could say, because of that,
it's easy to understand, even though it's low level code.
So low level code is not bad, it's necessary.
You need to write it somewhere.
But, you should right it in places where interpretation
is added by the name of the function in which
that low level code runs.
Now on the other hand,
if you have a look at this example here,
then you see that this could be harder to interpret.
This function is called saveUser,
and having this low level code in there
is a bit more difficult.
Because here the function name saveUser
does not add any interpretation to the low level code.
We have to figure out as a developer
that this low level code is probably executed
to validate some input.
It makes sense that we have a validation step
as part of saving a user,
but the actual low level code is a bit harder
to interpret than if it's close to
the level of abstraction implied by the function name,
as we have it on the left side here.
If a function is called saveUser,
it should just orchestrate all the steps
that are required to save a user.
So here we got a two big gap between
the level of abstraction implied by
the function name and the level of abstraction of
the actual operation we do in this function.
And I know that this can sound super overwhelming
and confusing.
It is something that comes with experience,
and where just thinking about it is already worth a lot.
Now levels of abstraction also matter because
of one other concept.
And I will also come back to that example
I showed you in the last lecture again, no worries.
But here's the other concept where levels
of abstraction also matter.
You should try not to mix multiple levels of abstraction
in one of the same function.
Here's an example, in this code here we're mixing
different levels of abstraction.
We got this quite low level email includes code
and the higher level users save code.
If we read the snippet,
we need to add quite a lot of interpretation to it,
to fully understand what's going on.
If this would be written like this,
all the operations would be on
the same level of abstraction,
and it would be easier to understand this.
If you read that, you really just need to read
the names of these functions,
assuming that they are properly named,
and you fully understand what this code does.
This is why levels of abstraction matter
and why mixing different levels,
or having a two big gap between the function name
and the operations done,
why that can cause problems and leads to bad code.
And if we come back to the example from before,
then the original function suffered from multiple problems.
Most importantly,
the gap between the level of abstraction implied
by the function name, renderContent,
and the levels of abstraction of the actual operations
we're doing here, was too big.
We got a bunch of low level operations in there,
like comparing the element
or concatenating our opening tax down there.
In the clean function example, that's not the case.
We got operations, which are one level below
the level of abstraction implied by renderContent here,
validateElementType,
createRenderableContent, renderOnRoot,
it makes sense that these are the steps
we need to go through to render some content to the screen.
So if we call renderContent,
it makes sense that these are steps
that need to be executed.
The actual work, which needs to be done,
the lower level operations,
are then outsourced into other functions
and in the functions to which we outsource them,
they then again, make sense.
In validateElementType, it makes sense
that we do comparisons like this.
Here, this low level code is absolutely okay.
And that's my levels of abstraction matter
and how you can ensure that you write clean functions.
Now, as I mentioned before,
this is a challenging and difficult concept.
It is something which comes with experience,
and even after a years of development,
you will still sometimes write functions
which are not clean.
As always, it's also not a hard rule,
if you have a very short function
with mixed levels of abstraction,
that could be fine, if it's easy to understand.
Nonetheless, it is important to always think
about that and to at least consider splitting a function.
And we're going to have a demo
and a challenge in the next lecture
where we practice this at a simpler example.
And we're also going to learn about a couple of
other related concepts throughout the rest of this module.