Now up to this point,
I showed you a lot of theory
and I talked about different levels of abstraction.
And I did show you some examples on the slides,
but now it's time for a real code demo
to make sure that this is all really crystal clear.
Here, we have a function createUser,
which takes the email and the password.
And we could also refactor this to take just one parameter
with an email and password field in a map, for example,
but I'm actually happy with the number of parameters
instead it's the function body on which I wanna focus here.
And we see this is obviously not a super long function
and reading and understanding it probably
won't take you too long.
Still it can be faster, I would argue.
Because we are doing a couple of different things here.
We are doing more than one thing,
and we have different levels of abstraction.
We have all this low level validation code up here.
We have the low level error output code,
but then we have the higher level insert call
on some database object.
We don't write the SQL query on our own here for example,
that would be lower level and we're not doing that.
So we definitely have mixed levels of abstraction here.
And in addition to these mixed levels of abstraction,
we also clearly have a too big distance between the name
of the function createUser and the actual work
we're doing in there.
This low level validation code,
where we check for an at symbol in the email,
that error message console log statement here
that is all too far away from the name, createUser.
If we read this code,
we have to think about the code
to come up with an interpretation.
It's not obvious by the name of the function
that checking for an at sign means that we're validating.
We at least have to think about that for a second.
The same for this console log statement.
It's not obvious that we're showing an error message here.
This is only clear if we have a look
at the surrounding code as well.
It's not enough to just have a look at the function name,
hence the distance is too big.
And if we would consider our rules of thumb here,
both rules would apply.
For one we got multiple validation steps,
which we could extract.
So that left side applies.
We have multiple lines of code or multiple parts
in the code, which deal with the same operation
or with a related operation.
Also down there for creating a user
and then saving that user.
That's also kind of related, you could argue.
And in addition, we got code that requires
some more interpretation than surrounding code.
This entire validation error handling part,
as I just explained, requires more interpretation
than this code down there.
Especially calling insert on a database object
requires very little interpretation
because it is pretty clear what it does.
It requires definitely less thinking from our side,
than this validation code at the beginning of this function.
Hence we got multiple strong signs that we should refactor
and split this function to make it cleaner.
So how could we rewrite this function now?
Well, let's do it together step by step.
And of course, feel free to try this on your own first.
You can pause the video and try coming up
with multiple functions instead of this one single function,
which work together such that all the functions
are very readable.
Here's your chance to pause the video
and try this on your own thereafter
we're going to do it together.
So were you successful?
Let's refactor this together.
Now we have these different levels of abstraction.
So I think one obvious first step
would be that we remove this validation logic
from this create user function.
We can cut it and add a new function below,
createUser to have to readable top to bottom flow
we learned about and named his InputIsNotValid for example,
and we take the email and the password here
and simply returned a result of the check which we cut.
And then here we call if InputIsNotValid
for email and password and therefore,
we have a very readable createUser function.
This now reads smoothly.
If InputIsNotValid for the email and password,
then we console log this and return.
Otherwise, if we didn't return this code executes.
So now this function is already more readable
just because we added this new function here.
And if you don't like the negative wording here,
you could, of course, all the named is InputIsValid
and reverse these check, wherever email is.
Truthy, and the email includes the at symbol
and we do have a password and trimming the password
and checking that trim password with that is not equal
to an empty string.
Then this would be valid.
And then here we could call InputIsValid
and check for the opposite here.
So if not InputIsValid for email and password,
then we do this, but that's just a wording thing.
The main thing is that we extracted our logic
and moved it into a different function.
Hence this level of abstraction is now in its own function
where we now have one equal level of abstraction.
This code here is all on the same level of abstraction.
And hence here, we actually still have some mixed levels,
but at least the input validation
is now on a kind of similar level as this code down there.
So it is an improvement.
It's not the last improvement we can make, though.
For one there will be more extraction possibilities
in this code, but even if we have a look at InputIsValid,
we could argue that we are doing more
than one operation here.
We could argue that we are doing four operations.
We check whether the email address is truthy.
We check whether it includes the at symbol,
whether the password exists and if it exists,
whether it is not empty.
So we are doing four things down there,
but we are doing them on the same level of abstraction.
And hence we could leave it like this.
Therefore let's focus on the rest
of this createUser function.
There we still have other levels of abstraction in there.
For example, logging this error here.
This is a low level operation
using the built in console log functionality,
which JavaScript offers both in Node.js
as well as in the browser.
Therefore, we could outsource this as well
and add a new function, show error,
or show error message for example,
where we take the message as an argument
and where we then console log a message
and advantage of creating this separate function
also would be that we could use
it in different places of our program
if we need to show errors in different places.
And if we ever decide that console log is not the mechanism
we wanna continue with,
we can easily use a different error logging mechanism,
and we only need to change it in one place
in this function instead of in multiple places.
So that's another reason
why creating a separate function here might make sense.
And now here we could simply call, showErrorMessage,
which again is on a higher level than console log in.
Now what about the code down there?
This is definitely on a higher level
than our validation checks here or console log,
but we could argue it's not on the same high level
as this code, but this is also something you
can always argue about.
But we could, for example, create a new function
which we name saveUser, where we take an email and password
as our argument and where we then take this code
and move it into this function.
Though we could argue whether the creation of the object
should really be in this function.
Alternatively, we could take the finished user
as an argument here and just do the database insertion.
Here I'm doing both, but again this is something
we could argue about and general when it comes
to writing clean code, even though we have a couple of rules
and concepts we can take into account,
it always will also come down
to a certain amount of personal preference
and it will leave room for discussion.
Nonetheless, here we could now call,
saveUser and forward to email and password here.
And therefore this createUser function
is definitely way more readable than before.
Now this function, as we have it here
could still be split up even more though,
because you could argue that all these operations,
all these lines of codes we have entry and user
are still not necessarily on the same level of abstraction
and also not all exactly one level below the function name,
implied level of abstraction, saveUser probably is.
That should be fine.
It makes sense that as part of creating a user,
we save a user, but this entire validation
overall makes sense.
But the individual steps which are involved
are actually on a lower level, checking the input validity
and showing an error message that is not necessarily
the same level of abstraction as just calling saveUser.
Therefore, we could argue that we want one extra function,
which we extract.
The let's say validateInput function,
where we take the email entity password as a parameter
and where we then in the end run this code here.
So that we become call validateInput here
and forward email and password,
instead of doing these steps in createUser.
Of course we can't just replace it like this though,
because returning here in validateInput will not return
and create user and will therefore not cancel
the rest of this function.
So therefore we could, for example,
switch and not show the error message here and return
because we could also argue that showing the error message
is not necessarily something we wanna do directly
invalidate input, because there we should
really just validate, but instead
we could throw an error here.
We could throw a new error where we have our invalidInput
messaged as an error message.
This is how we could do this in JavaScript,
there is a built in error object, which we can instantiate
and then throw with the throw keyword.
And if we do that, this error would bubble up,
would therefore also reach this function.
And if it's not handled here,
it would cancel this function and bubble up even further.
And now it would be somewhere above this function.
So where we call, createUser,
where we should handle this error
and where we then should call, showErrorMessage.
And that indeed is a code structure that might make sense.
And that would be the cleanest possible code here.
So for example, depending on which kind of application
we are building,
we could have a handleCreateUserRequest function
somewhere in our project code where we do call createUser
and we therefore here handle this error
and show this error message.
And this might be the cleanest way of writing this all
because now if we go back
to the original createUser function,
we see that we only have two operations in there,
which are on the same level of abstraction
and which both belong to createUser
and are one level below the level
of abstraction implied by createUser.
It makes sense that as part of creating a user,
we validate the input and we then save the user.
And hence, this is the final form of this function,
which I would call clean.
Obviously these were a lot of refactorings
and we did extract quite a lot of functions as part of that,
but that is what writing clean code is all about in the end.