Now, besides the levels of abstraction
and the different kinds of operations
you might be doing in a function,
there is another reason for
why you might want to split a function into smaller pieces.
And that would be Reusability, because reusability matters
at least sometimes.
In programming whenever you write any code
there is one very important rule,
which you should try to follow as often as possible,
in the best case of course you should always follow it.
And that rule is that you shouldn't repeat yourself,
don't repeat yourself write DRY code,
that's something you will hear a lot and DRY code
simply means code where you don't repeat yourself.
And this is not a complex concept at all,
it simply means don't write the same code
or very similar code in more than one place.
Because if you do, you are repeating yourself,
and what's the problem with repeating yourself?
Well, whenever you need to change something about that code,
some logic or some error,
then you need to make this change in multiple places
throughout your application if you did repeat yourself,
if you never repeated yourself
then you only need to make the change once,
which is of course way better.
Now, here are some signs for a code which is not DRY.
So where you are repeating yourself,
one obvious sign of course is that you
find yourself copy and pasting code.
If you're doing that you are obviously repeating yourself,
but another sign would be
that you do need to change something,
and you see that you need to apply basically the same change
in different places in your code base.
Well, the reason for that probably
is that you did repeat yourself.