Now here's an example
where we do repeat ourselves.
By the way, don't wonder why the createUser function
looks different than the final function forum
we derived before,
I will simply dive into errors and handling errors
in the next course section
therefore, I again removed that code
which would have been the perfect final code though
just to make this clear
and I went back to this second best solution here
where we actually have more levels of abstraction
inside of create user,
but that's not the function we're going to focus on anyways.
This createSupportChannel function is new,
it's a dummy function which doesn't actually do a lot
but it does one important thing,
it takes an email address because with that,
we then for example create a new support channel
where customers can contact us whatever.
And this email needs to be validated
before anything is done with it.
This of course should sound familiar.
We did already validate an email when we created
a user in the createUser function up there.
Here we got this input is valid validation function
where we do also validate the email together
with the password.
So in the end, we have some duplication here.
It's not exactly the same code because down there
we check for the positive case
and here we check for the negative case
but it's the same goal in the end and that's important,
code duplication and repeating yourself
does not mean that it's always the exact same code
but that is the same task you are doing,
the same logic you have and here it's definitely the same.
By the way also for the error message,
we're logging an error message here while we did this
in createUser as well,
there we then just created this show error message function
which we are calling.
Now because we created this showErrorMessage function,
we can at least get rid of this console log duplication
because if we ever would decide
that we don't want to log errors to the console
but handled differently, we would have to make
this change down there in show error message
and if we don't use this function here,
we would have to make this change here as well
that's exactly why we don't want to repeat ourselves.
So here we can of course also use show error message
instead of calling console log
and we already improved this code.
But what about the email validation?
Well, the fact that we need to validate
an email here as well but not a password
could be another reason for splitting up
this code even further.
Without the new create support channel function,
there wasn't really a strong reason
for splitting inputIsValid into multiple sub functions.
But with the existence of this new function,
there is a strong reason.
Because now we could add a new function,
emailIsvalid which takes just an email address
which in the end returns this part here
and in input is valid here,
we could then just call email is valid
and forward the email and combine that
with our password checks.
And now that we have this extra function,
this email is valid function, we could use this here
in the createSupportChannel function as well.
Like this, of course, here we need to add
an exclamation mark now.
And with that, we re-factored this code to extract it
into a separate function and we did create this function
not because we needed to because input is valid
was unreadable or had mixed levels of abstraction.
No, but we did it because of reusability and to stay dry.
And this can be another reason for extracting functions
and for splitting up functions
because now we don't repeat ourselves
and that's something we indeed wanna avoid.
Now as a side note, because I did create
this separate emailIsValid function and inputIsValid,
we use this function combined with this code,
we actually do have mixed levels of abstraction again
in input is valid.
EmailIsValid is a higher level of abstraction
because that's not the actual work we're doing instead
it's just calling some other function this function
which will do the work but then we combined
this with code where we do actual low-level work.
Therefore here, we could consider
and we should strongly consider to create
another function which is the passwordIsValid function maybe
which takes a password
and which then does this password validation.
So that we cut this code and returned a result
of this code here in password is valid
and then here we just call password is valid
and forward this password.
And with that here, we would again,
have the same levels of abstraction
and hence input is valid is now clean again.
So that's just another side note
and a consequence of extracting
this extra emailIsValid function
which we did in order to stay dry.