Now, with all the splitting up we did,
and with all the reasons we have, or we might have,
for splitting up a function and shrinking functions,
there's one important thing though.
You should still always use your common sense.
You should still always question
whether it's now really improving readability
and maintainability if you split a function.
You should split your functions reasonably.
At least, that is my opinion.
You learned all these different rules and concepts,
like the level of abstraction, and these rules of thumb,
and that you should stay DRY,
but just blindly following all these rules
bears the danger of becoming too granular.
And just because you are granular, and you split your code,
won't automatically improve readability of your code.
Indeed, the opposite might be the case.
So make reasonable decisions and don't split your code
if you are, for example,
just renaming the operation which you extracted.
Don't split if finding the code which you extracted
will then actually take longer
than if you would've just left it in place,
because we need to scroll to that new function
or search for it.
And a good sign that you shouldn't split
is if you have problems coming up with a name
for the new extracted function.
If you feel like any name you give it is clashing
with the name of the function you extracted the code from,
then extracting the code might've been a bad idea.
And I got an example for this as well.
Consider this saveUser function here.
You could definitely argue
that we have mixed levels of abstraction here.
Having this user object, which I create like this,
is on a different level of abstraction
than calling insert on this database object.
So you could split this and add a new function,
which you could name buildUser.
This takes a email and a password
and then returns this object here.
So I cut this object and return it here,
and then here, I just call buildUser
and forward the email and the password,
so that saving a user now is a combination
of building a user and inserting a user,
which is, I would argue,
on the same level of abstraction again.
So this is a split we could make.
It's not horrible, but in my personal opinion,
it doesn't really help with readability too much.
It doesn't really improve the code.
Indeed, I would argue that we can check two
of these three indicators at the bottom of this slide.
In the end, we just renamed the operation.
Previously, we created a new object,
which was a user object,
as was clearly indicated by that name of this variable.
Because we used proper naming there,
it was easy to understand what this object is about.
Now, I outsourced this code
into a function called buildUser.
So in the end, that's just renaming the operation,
which was obvious before as well without too much thinking.
In addition, it is quite difficult
to come up with a good name for this new function.
I named it buildUser.
Now, you could argue that createUser would be better,
but this actually clashes with this function
which we have at the very top.
Now, you could of course argue
that this function should maybe be renamed,
and maybe you could do that, but still I am struggling
with coming up with a good name down there.
buildUser, createUser,
in the end, these are just synonyms,
and it is difficult to come up with a good name here
because we are just renaming the operation.
So this split here is one which you can make,
which is not horrible,
but which I would argue will not really improve readability.
And if you do this a lot,
you actually might have less readability and less clean code
than if you don't do it.
And of course, with experience, you'll get a better feeling
for when to split and when not to split.
In general, of course, all the rules, and guidelines,
and ideas I covered throughout the section
still apply though, as you can tell by all the examples
you find in the rest of this code file.
Now, if you would want to split this code
and not have mixed levels of abstraction in saveUser,
you could, for example, come up with a better solution
where you utilize a new User class, let's say,
which takes an email and password constructor,
where you then store email and password,
and this again, of course, is a JavaScript example,
but you could apply this concept
in any programming language.
And then, you could have a save method here
in this User class
in which you call database.insert this,
or you restructure the data which should be inserted
inside of this method.
And with such a class being added,
you could rewrite this down there
to simply create a user by calling new User
and forwarding the email and the password,
and then on that user, you could simply call save.
Now, this would be on the same level
of extraction in the end.
It would be one level below the saveUser function name.
And now, we actually did improve the code
because now we didn't just make a useless code extraction
or a code replacement,
but instead we restructured the logic,
and we changed the place where we manage the user data
and the database insertion.
That's now all being done in this User class.
So if you would want to refactor saveUser,
this could be the better approach
than using this extra function which we created before.
Of course, now, in theory, you could also move further
towards an object-oriented approach,
and you could add your validation logic
inside of this class as well,
but that would then be more a question
of your general architecture
and where you wanna have which code.
It's then only related to clean code to a certain extent.
I just wanted to bring this up here
to show you that this can also be a way of refactoring this
so that you don't have to make a split
which might not make too much sense.