Now we learned about side effects
and pure functions.
Let's now have a look at a couple of examples here
so that you really get a feeling for what a side effect is
and how you could mitigate it.
So here's a code file, which you as always find attached
and this code file contains three example functions.
Now, as so many code files,
you won't be able to really execute this file,
it's not doing anything,
it just has a couple of example code snippets.
And now I want you to pause the video
and have a look at these different examples here
and then try to identify all the side effects you can find
just add a comment next to them
or write them down on a piece of paper
and also think whether that side effect is expected or not
and if it's not expected,
how you could potentially avoid it and work around it,
or make it expected.
So take that chance to pause the video and do that
thereafter, we'll walk through that together.
Were are you successful?
Let's take a look.
And let's start with connect Database.
If we call a function named connect Database,
we do expect that a database connection is established.
This of course, would be a side effect.
It changes the overall system and program state.
It's an important difference
whether our program is connected to a database
or not, after all.
So therefore, we would expect a side effect
ends up to function and indeed, we do have one.
Actually we have two, but let's start with the first one.
This is the first one,
calling database connect is probably the code
that would really establish a connection to some database.
So this is the code which ultimately
will change something in our system,
and therefore this operation
will definitely be a side effect.
And again, it's not an unexpected side effect at all
so there's nothing wrong with calling this function here.
However, we do have a second side effect here.
Did you spot that side effect?
Well, in the end it states console log statement down there,
where we output whether we were able to connect or not.
Now, this is also a side effect,
because showing a message to the user
is a change to the system state.
Now the question is
whether it's okay to have this code here or not?
And you can definitely discuss this.
We do have a name connect Database,
which implies that a side effect will happen.
But it's this first side effect which we expected,
not necessarily the second one.
But that is not exactly the thing we could discuss.
Because you could also make the argument
that a function named connect Database,
indeed might also take care about the error handling
if that connection failed.
So you could argue that it's not unexpected
that we don't just connect to the database,
but that we also show an error message
if that connection fails,
because connecting to a database
does not just include the success case,
but also the failure case.
That is an argument you could definitely make,
and then having this adverse side effect
would not be unexpected.
You could however, also argue that the only thing
which is expected is indeed that the database connection
is established and nothing else.
If that's the case, you could solve this problem
by simply creating a new function,
which you could call in it App.
So a function which is called at the beginning
to initialize your app
and in there you call connect Database.
And you expect to get back a success value let's say,
and then you grab your console log message here,
and you check if it's not a success here,
in which case, your initialization ends
and you just showed us error message
and otherwise, you continue with other initialization steps,
which you might have.
And then connect Database,
we therefore just return did Connect,
which could be a true false value,
or originally returned by connect,
which then is in the end checked here.
This is something you could do.
Now, you could argue
whether we really need
(wave sound)
a separate connect Database function then
since that's the end, just renaming the operation
we're doing in there,
but it could be the case that we are doing more.
If for example, we could be preparing the connection, Uri
and we could be doing work here.
So ultimately, if we do more work,
having the separate function could make sense
if we really just call database connect,
then indeed Just rephrased the operation,
and hence extracting this extra function
might actually not be a good idea
and we should have went with it in it App function
right from the start.
And I'm just discussing all these different options
to also make it clear that clean code
always is something which depends on personal preferences
and the general context
and it's something you can argue about.
And that is important.
There is no single right or wrong solution.
But my goal with this course
is to show you many potential factors
which you should take into consideration
and many potential strategies you can use
to derive and write cleaner code.
And therefore, this here is now my solution
for this first example, as you can tell
by the discussion we had here,
definitely not the only solution
but now a solution where I would argue
that all the side effects are not unexpected
and where therefore we did write some clean code.
So let's now move on to the next function,
determine Support Agent.
Here, we're getting a ticket
and then in the end, we check the request type,
which seems to be stored in the ticket
to either find a Standard Agent, or Agent By Request Type,
and then we returned as agent.
Now, does this function have any side effects?
Well, it most likely does not,
maybe find Standard Agent and find Agent By Request Type
have side effects, but we wouldn't expect it
if we just have a look at their names.
I wanna point out however, that if these functions
would for example, send a HTTP request behind the scenes,
or if we would establish some database connection
inside of these functions,
we would of course, introduce a side effect.
Just looking at the name of these functions
we shouldn't expect that they do either of that though
but it also always depends on the general context
of your application, whether you could expect
that they do something like this.
For example, if you're building
a browser side web application or a mobile application,
you could expect that a find something method or function
does indeed send an HTTP request to a back end server
and then we would all of a sudden have a side effect here.
But if we don't have that context,
if we just have a look at their names,
we probably shouldn't expect a side effect to occur here.
So therefore, this function doesn't have any side effects.
It does not change the state of our system,
or any other state.
Now what about this last example is Valid?
Here, we get two parameters, and we validate this,
show this message and then return false or true.
This function clearly has a side effect
and it is an unexpected one.
If a function is named is Valid,
we expect to get back true or false.
And of course we do, but we expect nothing more than that.
We don't expect that anything else happens.
And here, we are also logging this message to the console,
which is more than just returning true or false.
This is a side effect, because it changes our system state
and it's an unexpected one as well.
So this is not good code.
The better solution here,
of course would be to take this code
and create a new function,
create User for example, as we had it before,
where we get our email and password
and in this function,
we then call if is Valid email, password
and if that's not the case, we console log that
and otherwise, we continue.
Now create User is a function
where this side effect could be expected
because validation and handling validation errors
that sounds like a task which is involved
in the user creation process,
but now is Valid is a clean function
because it does not have any side effects.
Indeed, this is not a pure function,
because for the same email and password values,
it will always return the exact same response values.