To conclude this module,
we'll have a look at another very important aspect
and that would be testing, specifically unit testing.
Of course, you should be testing your code.
So that means you should be running automated tests
and it would be even better if you would write your code
in a test-driven way.
This course it not about testing
or test-driven development though.
But unit testing will indeed help you not just
with writing error-free code
but also with writing clean code
because there's one simple question,
which you automatically have to answer
when you utilize testing.
Can you easily test a function?
If the answer to this is yes,
if you're not having any problems with side effects,
like data being written to a database,
which you typically don't want during testing,
and if you don't do 10 different things in one function,
which are then therefore difficult to test,
then it's great and you probably have clean code.
If the answer is no though,
if you find that one function
does too many things and you therefore have
to write many tests testing different things
for one and the same function,
or if you have a lot of side effects in there,
then you might wanna consider splitting up your function
so that you have multiple functions,
which are then easier to test.
And that is how unit testing
will help you write cleaner code
and especially will help you write slim
and focused functions
because it turns out that small functions,
which only do one thing
and which don't have unexpected side effects
are way easier to test than big functions.
Now, as an example,
here's a another dummy function, addProduct.
It's validating some input,
showing an error message
and then creating and storing a product
and therefore, of course,
it's very similar to the createUser example you saw earlier
in this module.
Now, obviously, we can immediately see by now
that we have mixed levels of abstraction here
and that the distance between the level
of abstraction of the function name
and the level of abstraction of certain steps
in that function is too big.
But even if we wouldn't see that,
we would face problems
when we try to write tests for this function.
Here are two dummy tests
as we could write them in JavaScript, for example.
And of course, no matter which programming language you use,
your tests will look something like this.
I got two test cases here.
And in the first case,
I test whether the overall creation
of the product works.
In the second case, I'm actually only interested
in the ID and I wanna find out
if the ID was generated correctly
because it turns out that my ID should be composed
of both the name of the product,
as well as some random number,
which is converted to a string.
Now, when writing these tests,
I can see and feel that something's wrong
with my addProduct function
because for one, we have an unwanted side effect,
not an unexpected one
but an unwanted one during testing.
We are writing a product to the database.
In addition, if I'm just interested
in testing whether the ID was created correctly,
I still have to run the entire addProduct function
including that unwanted side effect
just to then find out whether the ID
was generated correctly or not.
So therefore, this clearly signals to us
that something's wrong with the function.
We could test more.
For example, if validation fails.
For that, we would need to check
whether this function completes successfully or not.
And all these tests would run on the same function,
testing totally different things.
So clearly, this is not a great function.
We should split it up
so that we have multiple functions,
which are then easier to test.
This is how we could refactor this addProduct function
to be cleaner.
It's way shorter
and it's split up into multiple smaller pieces.
I have the validateProductData function,
which throws an error if we have invalid input
and even that is split up further
into the inputIsValid function
and then the reusable isEmpty
and hasMinValue functions here.
And the advantage of this
is that I now, for example,
can write tests, which only test the isEmpty function.
So I can only test this small unit now
and I can test parts of my validation
or also the entire validation if I wanted to
without running the entire addProduct function.
I can also test just the generation of an ID,
if I wanted to,
because I did extract an extra function for this.
So I could check whether an ID is generated correctly
without creating an entire product
and storing that product in some database.
And that is why unit testing helps you
with writing cleaner code.
You could derive this code
without unit testing as well.
But when writing tests
and when testing everything,
which I don't do in the solution,
I just have some examples here
but when testing everything,
you will automatically see
what should be extracted
and what should not be extracted
because you wanna extract as much as possible
to write as many tests as possible
as long as they make some sense, of course.
Now, we don't need to write any unit test for addProduct.
We could write an integration test for this,
but we do have all these unit tests,
which we can write
for the small extracted functions we have here.
That's why testing matters,
not just for avoiding errors
and bugs but also for writing clean code.